(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-18T00:24:57.517703",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
オー！パーティー！
Oh! Party!
はーい
Heeey!
あ、はい、始まりました。
Ah, yes, we have started!
おー、はーい / はーい
Oh, hi! / Hi!
ウキ！ / ウキ！ / ウキウキ！
Ooh! / Ooh! / Ooh ooh!
ウキウキ、ウキウキ
Ooh ooh, ooh ooh!
お、モンキーたちよ
Oh, my monkeys!
ウキウキ / ウキウキ
Ooh ooh! / Ooh ooh!
わー、わー、わー、みんなウキウキ
Wah, wah, wah, everyone is monkeying around!
もうミュートされてる
You're already muted!
ミュートされてる
I'm muted!
はははは！
Hahaha!
なんか、ボボボボボボボボボボ
It's like, b-b-b-b-b-b-b...
フブちゃんもなんか既にミュートじゃないけど、音がなんかボワボワしてる？
Even though Fubu-chan is not muted, does the audio sound muffled?
そうですね、そう、ボワボワしてる
Right, yeah, it sounds muffled.
ボワボワしてる？
It's muffled?
なんか、ゲームの音質が
Like, the game's audio quality is...
音質が悪いのかも
...maybe the audio quality is bad.
そうですね、なんか
Right, like...
なんかノイキャン入ってるみたいな音になってるけど
...it sounds like some noise cancellation is on.
これ、消せんのかな？
Can we turn this off?
いや、どうしようもないと思うな、これ
No, I think there's nothing we can do about it.
高い音をね、多分、拾ってくれないんだよね
It probably doesn't pick up high-pitched sounds well.
ノイキャンの音になってる
It sounds like noise cancellation.
じゃあ低く喋ればいいんですよね？
Then we should just speak in low voices, right?
低く喋ればいい
We should speak low.
低く喋れば大丈夫
Speaking low will be fine.
If we speak low, it's fine.
大丈夫、今日はちょっと低めでやっていこう
Alright, let's play with lower voices today.
低く喋るといいかも
Maybe it's better to speak low.
低かったら低かったで、ノイキャン入りそうだけど
But if we speak too low, noise cancellation might still kick in.
それは、そう
That's true.
そこまで低く、低く切らすか？
Muffling it that low?
これ、ノイキャン入ってないですか？
Isn't noise cancellation turned on here?
もしもーし
Hellooo?
大丈夫です。でも、誰です、どちら様ですか？
It's fine. But who is this? Who are you?
Who are you? って感じですね、はい
Yeah, it feels like "Who are you?"
やっていきましょうか
Shall we get started?
えーっと、ルールは
Let's see, the rules are...
はい
Yes.
3匹の猿ですね
...three monkeys.
はい
Yes.
これ、これ、見ざるが何だっけ？見えない猿？
So, what was "Mizaru" (see-no-evil) again? The blind monkey?
ブラインド！
Blind!
そう、ブラインドモンキー！
Yes, Blind Monkey!
ブラインドモンキー！
Blind Monkey!
で、言わざるが何？
And what's "Iwazaru" (speak-no-evil)?
ミュート！
Mute!
あ、ミュートモンキー！
Ah, Mute Monkey!
ミュートモンキー！
Mute Monkey!
そう
Right.
で、聞かざるが
And "Kikazaru" (hear-no-evil) is...
デフ！
Deaf!
デフ？
Deaf?
デフ！
Deaf!
デス？
Death?
デスじゃないですよ、デフ
It's not death, it's deaf.
デスじゃないです
Not death.
デスモンキー！やばい
Death Monkey! That's bad.
デスモンキー、ははは
Death Monkey, haha.
デスモンキー
Death Monkey.
ちょっとこれ
Wait a sec.
デフモンキーに分かれて、なんかやっていく
We split into Deaf Monkey and others, then we do this.
爆弾を解除してくっていうゲームらしいんですけど
Apparently, we have to defuse a bomb.
1回もやったことがないので
Since I've never played this before...
ないです
...me neither.
どういうゲームなのかも全然、想像ができない
I can't even imagine what kind of game it is.
そうなんだよね、で、どうしようか、これ一応ランダムもできる、ランダム。
Exactly. What should we do? We can choose random too.
おお！
Oh!
ランダムにしてみる？
Shall we try random?
オッケー！
Okay!
オッケーです
Okay.
どうなるのか、ま、やってみよう
Let's see what happens and just try it.
そう
Right.
うん
Yeah.
難しそう
Looks hard.
あ
Ah.
聞こえない！
I can't hear!
バナナ
Banana.
ふふっ
Hehe.
え？
Eh?
Huh?
え？
色？
Colors?
下？下？
The bottom? The bottom?
下？
The bottom?
えー、えー...
Uh, uh...
I'm assuming we have to cut...
...the thing.
Is there like a red thing? What color?
Green?
緑？
No?
The instructions are on the floor.
There's a floor?!
Oh, they can hear me, oh right!
I'll explain the bomb. えっと...
I'll explain the bomb. Well...
4つの...
there are four...
えー、色のラインがあります。
uh... colored lines.
で、
And...
えーっと、左から緑、赤、
uh, from the left: green, red,
バナナ、ブルーです。
banana, and blue.
な、何色ですか？
Wh- what colors?
あの、同じ色のものを...
Like, the things with the same color...
おっ...
Oh...
あ、30秒！
Ah! 30 seconds left!
あ、緑、緑！
Ah, green, green!
緑かな？
Green, maybe?
え、か、こ...いやいや、カットできる？
Wait, cu- th- no wait, can you cut...
これ？これか？これじゃない！
This? This one? Not this one!
はっ、はっ！
Huh? Huh?
ねねちゃん...
Nene-chan...
ねね、何やっていいか分からなくって
Nene didn't know what she was supposed to do,
切る、切るボタンが出てきたから、あの...
but since a "cut" button appeared...
まあ多分、何番目を切るみたいなのは、見えない人がやるかも。
Maybe the blindfolded person is supposed to choose which one to cut.
あ、そっか！
Ah, I see!
色が見えないか！そうそう！そうじゃん！
Because you can't see the colors! Yes, yes! Of course!
イナちゃんが多分全部見えてて、それを多分イナが見たのを伝えて私がやるのかな、今の感じだと。
Based on how it felt, Ina-chan probably sees everything, tells me what she sees, and then I execute it.
そう、で、イナのも多分私を伝えてた。
Yes, and Ina was probably also relaying things to me.
あの、コードが多分4つあったんだけども、
So, there were probably four wires, but...
その解除方法が、カラーコードと多分ランプが点いてるのね。
the defusal method probably involves both the color code and a lamp.
ランプ...
A lamp...
そうそう、ランプを照らし合わせなきゃいけなかったっぽくて
Yes, yes, it seems we had to cross-reference with the lamp.
あぁ...
Ah...
で、バナナ切っちゃった。
And then she cut the banana.
あの、何か順番があったんだけど、その順番を、コードとその上にあるランプの色
There was an order to it, but that order is determined by the wires and the color of the lamp above them...
が...伝えられないっていうね。これ一通りやんなきゃ難しいな。
which we couldn't communicate. This is hard without doing a practice run.
え、ちょっともう一回やってみよう。
Let's try it one more time.
なんだか分かんないけど、もう一回やってみよう。
We don't really get it yet, but let's try again.
じゃあ、もう一回やってみよう。ランダムスタート。
Alright, let's try again. Random start.
ランプ？ランプの色？
Lamp? The color of the lamp?
えー...緑...
Uh... green...
かな？
maybe?
み、緑の...
The... the green...
ズーム。おっ。
Zooming in. Oh.
で、えーっと、ラインが4つあって、
And... uh, there are four lines,
左から赤、
from the left: red,
青、バナナ、緑です。
blue, banana, green.
これボットは何？
What is this bot?
あ、かな？モジュールを説明して。
Ah... maybe? Describe the module.
えーっと...
Well...
画面があって、上...あの、3つのコードがあって、
there is a screen, and above... uh, three wires,
上から、イエロー、緑、ブルー。
from the top: yellow, green, blue.
で画面で、真ん中はタイマーと、下X
On the screen, the timer is in the middle, and X is below
書いてます。
is written.
え？え？
Huh? Huh?
Light color? 「緑？」
Light color? Green?
ライトは緑？
The light is green?
Oh, just the light? What?
Oh, just the bottom one? I already said that!
えーっと、下は4つ
Uh, at the bottom, there are four
のワイヤーがあって、
wires,
左から赤、青、
from the left: red, blue,
バナナ、緑。
banana, and green.
バ、バナナってなんだっけ？黄色？
What was banana again? Yellow?
イエロー、イエロー、黄色。バナナ。
Yellow... yellow... yellow. Banana.
あ、その、えっと、その、あの、あの光ってるあれは、緑です。ライト。
Ah, the... that... the glowing light is green. The light.
あ、バナナ？えっと、左から3番目の、ワイヤーを切ってください。
Ah, banana? Um... Please cut the third wire from the left.
あ。
Ah.
左？ごめん、ごめん。
Left? Sorry, sorry!
今ので合ってるわ、ワンチャンある、ってなっちゃったよね。ごめん、ごめん。左右、右出ちゃいました。
We were like, "We might actually survive that!" Sorry, sorry. I got my left and right mixed up.
え、これ、あの、一番最初、ケーブルかどうか、っていうか、その、色んなパターンがあって、あの、なんか、ケーブル、多分どっちも、今2回ともケーブルだったんだけど、ケーブルじゃないこともあるから。
Also, for the very first one, there are different patterns other than cables... Both times we got cables, but there might be other things too.
あ、ちょっと、あの、マニュアル、見ます。そう、そうだね。じゃ、1回、ちょっと、イナちゃん、マニュアル、やってみるか？
Ah, let's take a look at the manual. Right. Shall I try holding the manual this time?
そうだね。
Yeah.
じゃ、上で、じゃ、あの、言わざるかな？
Then can you do the "speak no evil" one?
ああ、はいはいはい。ミュート、ミュートモンキーにできるから、ミュートモンキー、はい。
Ah, I see, I see. Since we can make you the mute monkey. Yes.
はいはい。で、じゃ、オッケー、これでオッケーかな？行ってみよう！
Alright. Okay, are we good with this? Let's go!
またかよ、っていう実績を達成した。あ。
I unlocked the "Again?" achievement. Ah.
おーい。で、あ、あー、なるほど。こう見えてるのか。
Okay. Ah, I see. So this is what it looks like.
あ、わ、またコードだ、コードだ。コード、コードだ。
Ah, it's cords again! It's cords!
いいな、コード。コードですか？左から、あ、これでも、これがあるんだよね。コード、コードがあって。
Nice, cords. Is it cords? From the left... Oh, we have these. There are cords.
グリーン。はい。え、イエロー。イエロー。
Green. Yes. And yellow. Yellow.
何もない、え、ブルー。
Nothing, then blue.
おー、3個、3個のコード。え、ケーブルです。
Oh, three. Three cords. Yes, cables.
あの、ランプ、ブルー。ランプ、ブルー。
And the light is blue. Light, blue.
ランプがブルー。3個。3個パターンで、ランプがブルーだった場合の、コードの色。
The light is blue. Three. In the three-cable pattern, when the light is blue, the cable colors...
ランプブルーの下のコード。えー、グリーン、グリーン、グリーン。
The cables below the blue light... Uh, green, green, green.
グリーンってどれ？グリーン、あ、これ。
Which one is green? Green... Ah, this one.
色がそう、だから。グリーン、グリーン。色、カラーがあっても。
Since the colors are... Green, green. Even if there's a color...
あ、グリーンを。グリーン、一番左、一番左のやつ、一番左のやつ。
Ah, green... Green, the leftmost one. Cut the leftmost one.
ナイス！ナイス、ナイス、ナイス、ナイス、ナイス！
Nice! Nice, nice, nice, nice!
ああー。あ、一個でいいんだ、これ。そうそう、一旦一個。ナイス！
Ahhh! Oh, only one was needed? Yeah, just one for now. Nice!
なるほど、はいはいはい。
I see, I see.
え、なんか、エモートはできる。ってちょっと、なんか、エモートの種類が、煽ってるエモートばかりで、使いづらい、すごく。
Wait, we can use emotes... But the emotes are all teasing ones, so they're really hard to use!
そう、そう。だから、伝える、周りのアイテムとかの色。はい。アイテム持ってね。そう。
Exactly. So you have to communicate using the colors of the items around you. Yes. By holding the items, right.
じゃ、じゃ、もう一回。次は、2モジュール、行ってみよう。はい。
Alright, let's go again. Next, let's try two modules! Okay.
お。
Oh.
おーい。
Hey.
あ、ケーブルですか？えっと、レバー。ランプ。
Ah, is it cables? Um, lever. The light...
レバー、え、左から、えー、レバー、黄色。え？え、イエロー、ブルー。
Lever... Um, from the left... Lever, yellow. Huh? Um, yellow, blue.
イエローと黄色、同じ。え、3番目が、レッド。え、イエロー？
Yellow and yellow are the same. Uh, the third is red. Wait, yellow?
4番目が、イエロー、イエロー。え、グリーン。
The fourth is... Yellow, yellow. Uh, green.
これかな？の、レバー。黄色とイエロー、同じだろ！
Is it this? The lever... Yellow and yellow are the same thing!
いや、怖い、やめて、やめて。怒らないで、怒らないで。えっと、今、
No, you're scaring me! Stop, stop! Don't get mad, don't get mad! Okay, so right now...
レバー、レバー4つ。左から黄色、青、赤、緑。あ、今度はコードモジュールじゃないね。レバー。レバーモジュールだ。
Lever, four levers. From the left: yellow, blue, red, green. Ah, it's not the cord module this time. It's the lever module.
アップ・アンド・ダウン・アコーディング・トゥ・ゼア・カラーズ。
Up and down according to their colors.
あ、そう、それだ、それだ。
Ah, yes, that's it! That's it!
このレバー、どのレバーを位置すればいいのか、みたいな感じだよね、多分、これ。
Which lever we should set to which position... That's probably it, right?
でも、なんか情報が必要なんだと思う。情報が。な、何このバー？バー？何？なんかこれ、バーをアップ、ダウン、アップ、ダウンみたいな、多分。
But I think we need some info. Info... What is this bar? Bar? What? It's like... up, down, up, down for the bars, probably.
オッケー、ダウン、アップ、ダウン。
Okay. Down, up, down.
え、黄色、上に、ってこと？うん、うん、うん。
So... yellow goes up? Mm-hmm, yes.
イエス。黄色、アップ。おー、そう、それ。黄色。
Yes. Yellow, up. Oh, yes, that. Yellow.
黄色。え、黄色、上。
Yellow... Uh, yellow, up.
あ、イエロー、2つあるんですけど。イエロー、上。
Ah, there are two yellows. Yellow, up.
オッケー。黄色を、
Okay. The yellow...
黄色、黄色、上に。で、黄色がどれだっけ？一番左、一番左、一番左。オッケー、オッケー。
Yellow, yellow goes up. But which one is yellow again? The leftmost one, leftmost, leftmost. Okay, okay, okay!
オッケー、オッケー。オッケー。
Okay, okay. Okay.
う、う、う、って私がうんうんしても伝わらないのか、これ。じゃ、次は？次は？えっと、ブルー、ブルー。
Wait, even if I nod like this, you can't see it. What's next? What's next? Uh, blue, blue.
ブルーは...
Blue is...
左から2番目のやつは
The second one from the left is...
下か？
Down?
下
Down.
オッケー、オッケー。赤は？
Okay, okay. What about red?
上、赤が上
Up. Red is up.
で、で
And, and...
緑は上
Green is up.
おー、いえーい！
Oh, yay!
おー、うまい！ すごいうまい！
Wow, nice! Very nice!
これが2個目のモジュールってことか
So that was the second module.
あ、なるほど、2個モジュールがあるわけじゃないんだ。あ、違うね。
Ah, I see. There aren't just two modules. Ah, never mind.
じゃあ次じゃあ、3個目のニューモジュール
Then next, the third new module.
オッケー
Okay.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
いや、ひなは喋れる。喋れる
No, Hina can talk. She can talk.
叩くのやめてね
Stop hitting me!
叩くじゃん
You're hitting me!
えっと、コード
Um, cords.
ケーブルが、スリーケーブル
The cable... Three cables.
で、ランプがレッド
And the lamp is red.
で、えっと
And, um...
左から、ブルー
From the left, blue,
グリーン
green,
イエロー
yellow.
ブルー、グリーン、イエロー。どれだ？
Blue, green, yellow. Which one is it?
There is no blue item!
どれだ？
Which one?
探してる、なんかすごい探してる
She's searching, she's searching hard.
コードと、一番最初のコードだな。コードの問題だ
Cords... The very first one is cords. It's a cable puzzle.
コード
Cords.
コードで、えっと
Cords, and...
なんか色探してんのかな。青い、青い色探してんのかな
Maybe she's looking for a color? Like blue?
コードが3つあって、ランプが今何色なのかわかんないけど
There are three cords. I don't know what color the lamp is right now, but...
でいいのかな
Is that right?
ね
Yeah.
スリーコード
Three cords.
ランプレッドだよ
The lamp is red.
ランプレッド
Lamp red.
あ、青だって
Ah, she says blue.
一番左
The far left.
オッケー、はい
Okay, yes.
で、次が
And next...
えっと、次がケーブルじゃなく、次のモジュールが
Um, next is not cable, the next module is...
レバー
Levers.
さっき、さっきやったレバーだね
The levers we did just now.
あ、4つのレバーで
Ah, the four levers.
左から、グリーン、ブルー、レッド、イエロー
From the left: green, blue, red, yellow.
オッケー
Okay.
グリーンが上
Green is up.
えっと、ブルー
Um, blue...
ブルーは
Blue is...
上
Up.
ブルー上？オッケー
Blue up? Okay.
えっと、レッド
Um, red...
上
Up.
上、はい
Up, yes.
えっと、イエロー
Um, yellow...
イエロー？
Yellow?
下
Down.
おおー！
Oh!
すごい！天才！
Amazing! Genius!
天才なんだけど！理解度が高すぎる！
You're a genius! Your understanding is way too high!
これフレアになった瞬間終わるやつだ
This'll end the moment it's Flare's turn.
絶対伝わんない。すごい！
It absolutely won't get through. Amazing!
天才、天才、天才！
Genius, genius, genius!
3モジュールかな？3モジュールで、タイムリミット3分。スリーミニッツ
Three modules? With three modules, time limit is 3 minutes. Three minutes.
はいはいはい
Right, right, right.
チェンジしてみる？
Should we change it?
ランダムいこう
Let's go random!
よし
Alright.
あ、ふうちゃんにめっちゃしばかれてるから
Ah, Fuu-chan is beating her up a lot.
うわ、何も聞こえない！えっと
Whoa, I can't hear anything! Um...
うわ、なんかニューモジュールいっぱいきだけど
Whoa, there are so many new modules!
一回、一番右の、レバー行こうか、レバー
Let's do the levers on the far right first.
はい、レバー。オッケー
Yes, levers. Okay.
オッケー、レバー
Okay, levers.
レバーいくよ。レバーが4つあります。はい
I'll do the levers. There are four levers. Yes.
で、左からレッド、ブルー、グリーン、イエロー
From the left: red, blue, green, yellow.
レッド、ブルー、グリーン、え？
Red, blue, green... wait, what?
え？何も押してない、今！
Wait, I didn't press anything just now!
何も触ってないよ、今！
I didn't touch anything just now!
え？なんで？
Eh? Why?
急に死ん...急に死んじゃった
Suddenly dead... Suddenly died.
急に死んだけども、今
Suddenly died just now.
なんか押した、今？
Did you press something?
わかんない、なんかボタン押したのかな
I don't know, maybe I pressed a button?
過保護ですね。制限時間か？
Overprotective. Was it the time limit?
いや、いや、3分あるから、もう一回行こうか、じゃあ
No, no, we have 3 minutes, so let's try again.
あ！
Ah!
オープン！
Open!
あ、またスリーモジュール。えっと、じゃあ一番右下いこう。一番右下、レバーです
Ah, three modules again. Um, let's go bottom-right. The bottom-right is levers.
レバー。4つのレバー、フォーレバー
Levers. Four levers, four levers.
オッケー？オッケー、オッケー、オッケー
Okay? Okay, okay, okay.
えー、左から、レッド、イエロー、ブルー、グリーン
Um, from the left: red, yellow, blue, green.
あ、左から...
Ah, from the left...
えっ！？
What!?
なんでー！？
Why!?
なんで爆発... クリックしました？
Why did it explode... Did you click?
なんで？なんか勝手に爆発するやつがある説？
Why? Is there something that explodes on its own?
なんか、なんか左下になんかあるっぽいね、時間制限が...
It looks like there's something on the bottom left, like a time limit...
あ、いえ、私が... 間違えてクリックしました、何か。間違えたかも
Ah, no, I... accidentally clicked something. I might have made a mistake.
あ、タッチ... 制限時間があるかな。見てみよう
Ah, touch... Is there a time limit? Let's check.
あ、でも24秒で爆発するやつあるみたい
Ah, but it seems there is one that explodes in 24 seconds.
おー、なるほど。オッケー
Oh, I see. Okay.
あ、やっぱり一番下の左の
Ah, as I thought, the bottom-left...
オッケー、一番下
Okay, bottom...
それ、レバー、一本しかないレバーのやつ？グリーンレバーみたいなやつ
Is it the one with only one lever? Like a green lever.
グリーンレバー？
Green lever?
あ、ひたすら触らなきゃいけないやつだ
Ah, it's the one you have to keep touching.
なんかびっくりマークついてるやつある？今
Is there one with an exclamation mark right now?
あ、はいはい、あります
Ah, yes yes, there is.
あ、操作してる人が触ったらいいんだ
Ah, the player has to touch it.
そう。あ、ちょっとずつ、あ、そのレバーを下げ、下げて、定期的に下げなきゃいけないんだ。
Right. Ah, little by little... Ah, I have to lower, lower that lever... I have to lower it periodically.
そうそうそう！
Right, right, right!
オッケー。はいはいはい。オッケー、それはじゃあ大丈夫です。
Okay. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay, then that one is fine.
理解してるじゃないか、理解してるじゃないか。
Aren't you understanding? Aren't you understanding?
4つのレバーのやつを…
The one with the four levers...
アップ、ダウン、アップ、ダウン。
Up, down, up, down.
やりたい。2ページ目のやつかな。
...I want to do. Is it on the second page?
で、えっと…左から、ブルー、イエロー、レッド、
And, let's see... from the left, blue, yellow, red,
グリーン。なんで、ブルーからお願いします。
green. So, blue first, please.
ブルー？見えない。え、トライ。
Blue? I can't see it. Eh... Try.
どうだった？あ、ブルー来た、来た。
How was it? Ah, blue's here, here.
ブルー下？
Blue down?
はい。下、下。ブルー下。
Yes. Down, down. Blue down.
下、下。
Down, down.
えーっと、1番…そうそう。で、次がイエロー。
Let's see, the first... right, right. And next is yellow.
イエロー下。
Yellow down.
下。下。下？
Down. Down. Down?
えっ、左から2番目が下。
Eh, the second from the left is down.
はい。
Yes.
で、えーっと、レッド。
And, let's see, red.
アップ。
Up.
次が上。
Next is up.
はい。グリーン。グリーンアップ。
Yes. Green. Green up.
グリーンも上。
Green is also up.
おお。次がちょっと新しいモジュールなんですけど、
Oh. Next is a somewhat new module,
はい。
yes.
なんか、えっと…ゲーム、ゲーム機みたいな、なんか十字キーがあって、
like, let's see... like a game, a game console, there's a D-pad,
真ん中にボタンが3つあって、ランプがブルー。
with three buttons in the middle, and the lamp is blue.
めっちゃ叩いてくれ。ランプがブルー？はい。
Smash it hard. The lamp is blue? Yes.
えっ、6って書いてある。
Eh, it says 6.
十字キーは赤い十字キーが、三角のやつが4つ付いてる。
The D-pad has a red D-pad, four triangle-shaped things are on it.
6！6！
Six! Six!
どっち押さなきゃいけないんだろう。
Which one do I have to press?
6！6！6！6！
Six! Six! Six! Six!
6、6？え、と、どういうこと？51？
Six, six? Eh, what does that mean? 51?
51。
51.
51？えっ、これかな？
51? Eh, is it this one?
黄色、バナナ持ってるけど。黄色かな？
Yellow, I have a banana though. Maybe yellow?
下。下？下だって。下。
Down. Down? She says down. Down.
下。あっ、下、下？いや、いや、いや。
Down. Ah, down, down? No, no, no.
え、違う？下は、あれ、バツ？
Eh, is it wrong? Is down, wait, "X"?
バナナ。
Banana.
あっ、黄色、黄色くなった、ランプ黄色くなりました。
Ah, yellow, it turned yellow, the lamp turned yellow.
イエロー、ランプ、イエロー。
Yellow, lamp, yellow.
6！7！
Six! Seven!
6、7？
Six, seven?
十字キーのどれかを押すんだと思うんだけど、
I think we press one of the keys on the D-pad,
こ、こっちじゃなかったっけ？違うモジュール。
W- wasn't it this one? Wrong module.
ああ。
Ah.
上下、右左。あっ、で、ボタンが4つになった。
Up down, right left. Ah, and there are four buttons now.
真ん中のボタンが、え、4つ。
The middle buttons are, eh, four.
7！7！
Seven! Seven!
な、なな？
Se- seven?
いな、困ってる。
Ina is troubled.
いな！はい！
Ina! Yes!
いな！十字で、真ん中が点が4つあるやつ。
Ina! The D-pad, the one with four dots in the middle!
あっ。これ、新しいやつだ。点が、点が4つある。
Ah. This is the new one. There are dots, there are four dots.
そう。あっ、そう。これ、あ、ボタンじゃなくて、点って言った方がよかったかな。
Right. Ah, right. I should've said dots instead of buttons, huh?
あ、これか。4つ、そう, 4つあって、点があったんだよ。
Ah, this one. Four, yeah, there were four, there were dots.
で、なんか一回間違えると、なんかランプと、そのボタン、その点の色、数がある…
And if we make a mistake once, the lamp and the button... the color and number of dots change?
ああ。
Ah.
多分モニターの点の数によって、あの、上下左右。
Probably depending on the number of dots on the monitor, like up, down, left, right.
はいはいはい。多分どのボタンを押すか、だと思うんだよね。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I think it's about which button to press.
そうだね。
Right.
ああ。
Ah.
これ、これ叩いたよね。あの、りささん。
You smashed this, right? Rissa-san.
え？
Eh?
わけわからん。あるある。
I don't get it. Classic.
ね。あ、じゃあもう一回行ってみるか。
Right. Ah, shall we try again?
うん、行ってみる。でもなんか、ずっと、ずっと固定だね。
Yeah, let's try. But it seems to be stuck, stuck forever.
ね、あれ？ずっと固定だね。
Right, wait? It's stuck forever.
はい、はい。やめてね。
Yes, yes. Stop it.
えーっと、またじゃあ、レバーから行きます。
Let's see, we'll start with the levers again.
レバーだ、レバーだ。
Levers, levers.
4つのレバー。ランプなし。
Four levers. No lamp.
えっと、左がブルー。1番左からブルー、
Let's see, blue on the left. From the far left, blue,
上。1番左、上。
up. Far left, up.
ブルー上。で、次がレッド。
Blue up. And next is red.
レッド…
Red...
下？
Down?
下。えっ、下。
Down. Eh, down.
えっと、グリーン。
Let's see, green.
グリーン、下、下。
Green, down, down.
グリーン、下。
Green, down.
イエロー。
Yellow.
イエロー。イエロー、下。
Yellow. Yellow, down.
イエロー、下。オッケー。
Yellow, down. Okay.
次がさっきのなんか十字キーついてるやつで、
Next is the one with the D-pad from earlier,
点が2つで、ランプがブルー。
with two dots, and the lamp is blue.
ランプがブルー、ナイン。えっと、右。
Lamp is blue, nine. Let's see, right.
点が、点が。え、これって左、左でいいのかな？
Dots, dots. Eh, is this one left, left?
右？右、右。
Right? Right, right.
右。オッケー。
Right. Okay.
あれ？え、違う、ノー？
Huh? Eh, wrong, no?
ミス。ミス。
Mistake. Mistake.
ほどほど、あ。右が何でした？
Moderately, ah. What was right?
あ、これって。
Ah, this is...
あ、またレバーやってなかった。あの、あの、あれが必要なんです。ランプの色と、あの、点、なん、点の…
Ah, I didn't do the lever again. We, we, we need that. The lamp color, and, the dots, how many dots...
あのナンバー...
That number...
数だよね？
Is the count, right?
はい。
Yes.
ちょっと間違えました。
I made a little mistake.
右と左がさ、あの、イナの向いてるやつとこっちで向いてるやつで、違う、違うかも。やばい！ってなった。
I realized the left and right might be different depending on which way you and I are facing. I was like, "Oh no!"
ね。
Right?
あ、ちょっと変わってみるか？じゃあ、フブちゃん言わざるやってみたら？
Ah, should we switch roles? Why don't you try being the mute one, Fubuki?
オッケー。
Okay.
えっと、見ざる選べばいいの？
Um, should I choose the blind one?
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー。
Okay.
あ、じゃあこれでいいか。
Ah, then this is fine.
そう、一回行ってみよう。
Yeah, let's try it once.
オッケー。
Okay.
He said to know the dot and number. Okay, okay, okay.
あ、モジュールが...
Ah, the modules...
三つ。えっと、すら... あの、う、オッケーオッケー。
Three. Let's see, sli... that, uh, okay, okay.
えーっと、真ん中の点がある、あのモジュールです。
Um, it's that module with the dot in the middle.
で、ランプが...
And the light is...
赤、点が２です。
Red, dots is 2.
えっと...
Um...
これかな？うん。
Is it this one? Yeah.
あ、左？
Ah, left?
右？右？
Right? Right?
右？
Right?
右で合ってますか？
Is right correct?
右？
Right?
右。
Right.
あ、あ、it changed. あ、えっと、ランプが...
Ah, ah, it changed. Ah, um, the light is...
ランプが、黄色、あの、点が3。
The light is yellow, and the dots is 3.
右。
Right.
はい。
Yes.
えっと、ランプがグリーンで、点が２。
Um, the light is green, and the dots is 2.
また右ですか？
Is it right again?
あ。
Ah.
あ、上？
Ah, up?
あ、上です、上です。
Ah, it's up, it's up.
上です、はい。
It's up, yes.
緑のランプの、えっと、点が２だったら、上...
If the green light, um, has 2 dots, then up...
あ、上です。フブキ先輩。
Ah, it's up, Fubuki-senpai.
はい。
Yes.
えっと、赤のランプで、
Um, it's a red light,
点が、え？
and the dots, eh?
Oh, I don't know the number? Oh.
あ、赤のランプで、７ですか？フブキ先輩。
Ah, it's a red light, is it 7? Fubuki-senpai.
え、こ、８、８、８。
Eh, th... 8, 8, 8.
あ、赤のランプで、８。
Ah, red light is 8.
赤のランプで、８。
Red light is 8.
右、上？上、上。
Right, up? Up, up.
えっと、イエローのランプ、
Um, yellow light...
イエローのランプ、５。
Yellow light, 5.
上？
Up?
上。
Up.
そうか！
I see!
点と、見えている数が違う...
The dots and the number we see are different...
そうですね、はい、そうです。
That's right, yes, it is.
うん、なんかフブちゃんがさっき数字言ってたの、何かなと思ってたけど、そういうことだよね。
Yeah, I was wondering what those numbers Fubuki was saying earlier were, but that's what it meant.
そうです。だから、ニュイさんが...
Yes, so Nui-san...
私が見ている点と、あの、
The dots I'm seeing and, you know,
フブキ先輩が見ていた数が、
The numbers Fubuki-senpai was seeing,
点字っていうあの、
was Braille, you know,
見えない方が読む、あれ。点々。
the ones that visually impaired people read. The dots.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
だから、違って、はい。
So they were different, yes.
なるほど。
I see.
じゃあ、点字、点字。
So Braille, Braille.
あ、点字やってる人が数字を教えてあげなきゃいけないんだ。
Ah, so the person doing the Braille has to tell the number.
はい、で、私がランプの色見て、
Yes, and then I look at the color of the light,
フブキ先輩がナンバー見て、
And Fubuki-senpai looks at the number,
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
それだったんですよ、はい。
That's how it was, yes.
なるほどね。
I see.
ランダムで行ってみるか、じゃあ。
Let's try random then.
はい。
Yes.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー、カモン。
Okay, come on.
カモン。
Come on.
すげえ煽ってくる、この...
It's really mocking us, this...
えっ、またランプ、絶対、
Eh, also the lights, definitely...
どっちから行こうかな。
Which one should I go with?
さっきの、同じさっきのやつで行きます。
I'll go with the same one as earlier.
はい。
Yes.
左下から行くよ。フブちゃん、フブちゃんかな？
Going from the bottom left. Fubuki-chan... is it Fubuki-chan?
イナかわかんない。
I don't know if it's Ina.
えーっと、ランプがレッド。
Um, the light is red.
はい。
Yes.
で、ボタン、点字の数が、
And the button, the Braille number is...
9。
9.
下、下、下。
Down, down, down.
下です。
It's down.
え、どうですか？
Eh, how is it?
下、下。
Down, down.
下？
Down?
下、下。
Down, down.
え...
Eh...
次が ランプがイエロー
Next, the light is yellow.
はい
Yes.
点字が8
The Braille is 8.
8！
8!
イエローの8
Yellow, 8.
あ、イナには聞こえてるんだ そうだ
Oh, Ina can hear us. Right.
聞こえてるんだ
She can hear us.
右です
It's right.
左だっけ？
Was it left?
あ、これ右？
Ah, is this right?
右、右、右です
Right, right, it's right.
逆？
Opposite?
右、右、右！
Right, right, right!
右！
Right!
次が ランプがレッド
Next, the light is red.
4！4！
4! 4!
点字が4
The Braille is 4.
4！4！4！
4! 4! 4!
上。上。
Up. Up.
上。おっけー、ナイス！
Up. Okay, nice!
おっけー で、次が
Okay, and next...
ランプがイエロー
the light is yellow.
イエロー
Yellow.
数字が6！
The number is 6!
イエローの6
Yellow, 6.
点字が6
The Braille is 6.
右？左？
Right? Left?
あ、逆！逆です！
Ah, it's the opposite!
逆、逆！
Opposite, opposite!
違う、違う！
No, no!
あれ？違う？
Huh? Is it not?
あ、調整。調整、調整。
Ah, adjustment. Adjustment, adjustment.
ランプがブルー
The light is blue.
はい
Yes.
セブン、セブン！点字が7
Seven, seven! Braille is 7.
下。下。下。下。
Down. Down. Down. Down.
下？下。
Down? Down.
下かな？
Down, I think?
下、下。おっけー、ナイス！
Down, down. Okay, nice!
で、次が ランプがレッド 点字が8
And next, light is red, Braille is 8.
エイト、エイト、エイト！
Eight, eight, eight!
上。上。
Up. Up.
ナイス！
Nice!
次が ランプがグリーン 点字が4
Next, light is green, Braille is 4.
フォー、フォー、フォー！
Four, four, four!
さっき右、右だったんだよね
Earlier, it was right, right?
右。右、おっけー
Right. Right, okay.
あれ？右だ、左だ、これ？
Wait? Is it right or left?
これ フブキ先輩が逆だったから
Since Fubuki-senpai was reversed,
私が代わったんですよ
I swapped places.
私もなんか逆だと思って
I also thought it was reversed,
さっき、さっきと、なんか逆のこと言ったんだけど
so I said the opposite of what I did earlier.
じゃ、ここで決めますか
Then, shall we decide here?
左右もちょっと出ちゃうから 決めようか これ
Left and right can be confusing, so let's decide.
押す人から見て 右が左かでいいかな？
For the person pressing, should we use their left and right?
そうです はい
Yes, that's right.
押す側の人が右を向いたら こっちから見たら左になっちゃうから
Because if the presser turns right, it looks like left from here.
右 右 右手を...
So, right is right...
そうそう そういうこと
Right, exactly.
じゃあ またランダム行ってみよう
Okay, let's go random again.
あ、来た はい
Ah, here we go. Yes.
あ、また同じこと ありますよ
Ah, we have the same thing again.
えっと ランプ、青
Let's see, light is blue.
で、2です
And it's 2.
右ですかね？
Is it right?
あ
Ah.
えっと、えっと、
Let's see, let's see...
グリーンランプ、7 グリーン、7
Green light, 7. Green, 7.
上
Up.
えっと ブルーランプ
Let's see, blue light.
で、1
And 1.
右？右です、右
Right? Right, it's right.
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes.
イエローランプ、で
Yellow light, and...
え、9かな？イエローランプ、9
let's see, is it 9? Yellow light, 9.
右？
Right?
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes.
ブルーランプ
Blue light.
で、え、7
And, let's see, 7.
右？右ですか？あ、違う、違う
Right? Is it right? Ah, no, wait.
下？
Down?
下、下、下
Down, down, down.
はいはいはい
Yes, yes, yes.
これ、終わったかな？
Is this part done?
じゃ、終わったかな
I guess it's done.
じゃ、あのスライダー、4つのスライダーです
Okay, the sliders, the four sliders.
えっと、左から、え、赤
Let's see, from the left, red.
上？
Up?
下、下？
Down, down?
赤は下？
Red is down?
はい、赤は下です
Yes, red is down.
えっと、2番目は、え、バナナ、イエロー
Next, the second one is... banana, yellow.
イエローは、下ですか？
Is yellow down?
はい、イエローも下です
Yes, yellow is also down.
じゃ、緑。グリーン
Okay, green. Green.
グリーン、下？
Green, down?
はい、下です
Yes, it's down.
ブルーは？
What about blue?
上です
It's up.
イェーイ！
Yay!
やったー　やったー
We did it! We did it!
右と左のやつむずい
The right and left thing was hard.
右と左がもうやばい
My right and left are completely messed up.
やばいよね、右と左、ね
It's bad, right and left, right?
すげえ　すごい
Awesome! Amazing!
やったー！　やったー！
We did it! We did it!
素晴らしい　やった、ナイス！
Wonderful! We did it, nice!
3分絶妙だな
Three minutes is a perfect amount of time.
ね、じゃあ次が...
Right, then next is...
これは、次は、難易度5かなこれ
Is this... next is difficulty level 5, I think?
難易度5で、モジュール3つなのかなこれ、わかんないけど。やってこう！
With difficulty level 5, are there three modules? I don't know, but let's do it!
3って書いてるね　はい、次。じゃあランダムで...
It says three. Yes, next. Let's go with random...
ゴー！
Go!
あ、開きます
Oh, opening.
えーっと、誰だ、これ、えーっと...
Um, who is this? Um...
じゃ、スライダーから行こう。右下のスライダーから行きましょう。右下のスライダー
Let's go with the sliders. Let's start with the bottom right slider. Bottom right slider.
そうそうそう、右下のスライダーです
Yes, yes, yes, the bottom right slider.
左がイエロー
Left is yellow.
上
Up.
次がレッド
Next is red.
上、上と上
Up, up and up.
ブルー
Blue.
下
Down.
グリーン、上
Green, up.
で、あ、ニューモジュール
And, oh, a new module.
えーっと、ドットが10個ある？なんかテンキーみたいなの
Um, there are ten dots? Like a ten-key pad.
で、50+17みたいになってます
And it shows something like 50+17.
え？ 50+17？
Eh? 50+17?
どうしたらいいんだこれ、ドットが...
What should I do with this? The dots are...
67だけど、どうしたらいいんだこれ
It's 67, but what should I do with this?
ニューモジュール...
New module...
これ、足せってこと？全然無理なんだけど
Does this mean I should add them? That's completely impossible.
何て！？
What!?
これ計算して...
Calculate this...
これニューモジュールどうしたらいいんだ？"
What should I do with this new module?
あー、ランプの色...
Ah, the lamp color...
57にしろってこと？
Does it mean make it 57?
テンキーがある
There's a ten-key pad.
あ、全然、何をすればいい？
Ah, what should I do at all?
何、何を押したらいい？
What, what should I press?
え、色、色はドットですか？
Uh, color, is the color the dot?
どのボタンを押せばいいんだ？
Which button should I press?
色、色はドットですか？
Color, is the color the dot?
モジュール触ってる人は声出せるよ
The person touching the module can speak.
60、67にすればいいのか？
Should I make it 60, 67?
67ですか？本当に67ですか？
67? Is it really 67?
どうしたらいいんだ？
What should I do?
あ、67出てる、あれ？
Ah, 67 is showing, huh?
え？え？ランプ、ランプの色
Eh? Eh? Lamp, lamp color.
ランプがついた、イエローのランプが
A lamp lit up, the yellow lamp.
えーっと、色、色何ですか？
Um, color, what is the color?
わかんない！
I don't know!
色、色、赤、あ、イエロー
Color, color, red, ah, yellow.
67、67押せばいい、67押して
67, just press 67, press 67.
なんかグリーン、なんかグリーンになってる
It's green, somehow it's green.
どっち、どっちですか？
Which, which one is it?
バナナ、バナナ、バナナ！
Banana, banana, banana!
イエローじゃない、イエローが欲しい、色が欲しい
Not yellow, I want yellow, I want color.
イエローのランプがついてます。イエローランプ
The yellow lamp is lit. Yellow lamp.
えーっと、50+17、67って入れたらイエローのランプがつく。な、な、7？
Um, if you enter 50+17, 67, the yellow lamp lights up. Se- se- 7?
7？
7?
7！
7!
あ、オッケー！え、あ、オッケー、オッケー！クリア、クリア！
Ah, okay! Eh, ah, okay, okay! Clear, clear!
やった！なんか分かんないけど7って言われたから押したらできた
We did it! I don't know why, but they told me 7, so I pressed it and it worked.
これね、必要だったのが、あのランプの色と、あの計算して出たのが、えーっと...
For this, what was needed was that lamp's color, and what came out of the calculation, um...
odd or even、これ日本語で何だっけ？
odd or even, what was this in Japanese again?
えーっと、グーグル先生、 odd or even って何でしたっけ？
Um, Google Sensei, what was odd or even?
えーっと、odd or even...
Um, odd or even...
グーグル先生！
Google Sensei!
なんだろう。でも、一回足し算をするんだよな
What is it? But, you do addition once, right?
奇数か偶数か、奇数か偶数か
Odd or even, odd or even.
あ、奇数、なるほどね！奇数か、あ、なるほど
Ah, odd, I see! Odd, ah, I see.
とりあえず数字を伝えれば大丈夫だった
Anyway, as long as I told the number, it was okay.
はい
Yes.
で、なるほど。そこであのチャートがあって、あのナンバーを伝えたらあれをポチッと
I see. And then there's that chart, and if I tell you that number, you click that.
あー、なるほどね！
Ah, I see!
はい
Yes.
なるほど、なるほど。足し算して出た答えで奇数か偶数か見て、対応する番号を伝える
I see, I see. You look at the answer from the addition to see if it's odd or even, and tell the corresponding number.
合ってたんだ、ナイス！
It was right, nice!
おお
Oh.
素晴らしい
Wonderful.
奇数か偶数で合ってるんだったら、次に奇数、別に今7だったけど、7じゃなくてもよかったの？
If odd or even is correct, then next odd, it was 7 just now, but did it not have to be 7?
それとも7じゃないとダメだった？
Or did it have to be 7?
7じゃなきゃダメだったかな
I think it had to be 7.
はい、7が、あのチャートと、えーっと...
Yes, 7 is, that chart and, uh...
そうですね、なんか前の、あのランプの色と、線のナンバーで、なんか上、下みたいにチャートがあったんですよ。で、そこで...
That right, like, with the previous lamp's color and the line number, there was a chart like up, down. And there...
あ、なるほど
Ah, I see.
あの、ナンバーが書いていて、あの色と、あの、アレをマッチしたら、そのナンバーが合ってるっていう感じ
The number was written there, and if you match that color and that thing, that number is correct.
あ、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
へえ、おもろ
Wow, interesting.
むず！
Difficult!
むずいね。じゃあ、次もじゃあランダムで行ってみるか。オッケー！"
It's difficult. Well, shall we go with random next time too? Okay!
はーい
Okay.
あ、開きます
Oh, opening.
えーっと、わー、じゃあ、どうしようか、左上のスライダー行くか、スライダー
Um, wow, then, what should we do, shall we go to the top left slider, slider?
あ、スライダー。オッケーオッケーオッケー"
Ah, slider. Okay, okay, okay.
モジュール、え、左からイエロー
Module, uh, yellow from the left.
上
Up.
はい、レッド
Yes, red.
下
Down.
グリーン
Green.
上
Up.
ブルー
Blue.
ブルー、下
Blue, down.
あ、え？
Ah, wait, what?
あっ、そっか。スライダーがあった。
Oh, that's right. There was a slider.
あの、スライドダウンしたやつですね。
The one you had to slide down, right?
あー、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
初めて見た
That's the first time I've seen that.
もう一回、もう一回！
One more time, one more time!
お、オッケー。
Oh, okay.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
次何だこれ？いな？
What is this next one? Ina?
はい。
Yes.
いな、いなじゃ、いなじゃ、こっちがいなのモジュール。
Ina... wait, this one is Ina's module.
わっ、何だ？新しい...
Whoa, what is this? A new...
えっとじゃあ、左下の、スライダーいこう。レバー、レバー。
Okay, let's do the bottom-left slider. Lever, lever.
はい。
Yes.
レバー、オッケー？
Lever, okay?
オッケー。
Okay.
え、左から、イエロー。
Starting from the left, yellow.
下。
Down.
グリーン。
Green.
グリーン、上。
Green, up.
上、オッケー。
Up, okay.
レッド。
Red.
レッド、上。
Red, up.
え、ブルー。
Uh, blue.
ブルー、上。
Blue, up.
オッケー、ナイス！
Okay, nice!
えっと、次、えっと次コード、コード。
Okay, next is wires, wires.
コード。
Wires.
えー、4つのコード、4コード。
Uh, four wires, four wires.
4つのコードで...
With four wires...
えっと、赤いランプが点いてる。
Uh, the red lamp is lit.
何色？ワイヤー。
What colors are the wires?
ワイヤー。
Wires.
えっと、レッド、レッド、4本です、4本。
Uh, red, red, there are four of them.
4本で...
With four wires...
何番目？ブルー？
Which number? Blue?
また聞くわ、聞くわ。え、ブルー、ブルー、ブルー、ブルー、ブルー...
I'll read them again. Blue, blue, blue, blue, blue...
ブルー、オッケー、ブルーカット。
Blue, okay, cut blue.
左から何番？
Which one from the left?
あ、一番左、もう一番左。
Ah, the leftmost one, the very leftmost.
はい。
Yes.
オッケーオッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
えー、オッケーオッケー。で、次が、えっと、足し算。
Okay, okay. Next is, uh, addition.
えっと、51...
Uh, 51...
10... 41。
Minus 10... 41.
多分モニターに41って入力するのかな？
Maybe you enter 41 on the monitor?
41。
41.
え？41？私？
Eh? 41? Am I doing it?
41。
41.
私がやるんですか？
Am I the one entering it?
え？
Huh?
オッケー。レッド、ボタン、レッド。41でボタン、レッド。
Okay. Red, the red button. 41, then press the red button.
赤。
Red.
ナンバー、パーセンテージ。3、ナンバー、3。
Number, percentage. 3, number 3.
3。
3.
ナンバー3。
Number 3.
ナイス！
Nice!
おおーー！
Whoa!
やったー！
We did it!
あ、上手い！
Ah, nice job!
めっちゃ上手い！
That was amazing!
ナイス！
Nice!
理解、理解。終わって計算の意味が理解、理解。
I get it now. Now that it's over, I understand the math.
新しいモジュールが来てて、さっきのあの、ずっとレバーを下げなきゃいけないモジュールがあったじゃん？
A new module appeared. You know how we had to keep holding that lever down earlier?
はい。
Yes.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
今度は、なんか、ずっと連打して止めるやつがあった。
This time, there was one where you had to keep mashing to stop it.
はい、なんかプレッシャーの。
Yes, the pressure one.
そうそうそう、それ！
Yes, exactly that one!
あ、でも早かった。レバーと同じくらいのだ、多分。
But that was fast. It was probably similar to the lever.
ねー。
Yeah.
いながずっと連打してた、ポポポって。
Ina was mashing it the whole time, click-click-click.
じゃあ、次が4分だね。じゃ、じゃ、またランダムで行ってみよう。
Next is 4 minutes. Let's go with random again.
はい。
Okay.
おー。
Whoa.
えー、とにかくここのコードからいこっか。コードいきます。えっと、4本あります。
Anyway, let's start with the wires. I'll do wires. There are four wires.
ランプが、えー、グリーンです。
The lamp is green.
で、ケ、ケーブル... あ、これは別に言わなくてもいいのか。
And the ca... cable... Ah, wait, I don't need to say this.
うん。
Yeah.
あ、でも、切るやつを教えてください。順番に言っていきます。
Oh, but please tell me which one to cut. I'll list them.
はいはいはい。
Okay, okay, okay.
グリーン、グリーン、えっと、4番...左から4番目。
Green, green, uh, 4th... 4th from the left.
あ、あれ？
Wait, what?
違う、違うらしい。
No, that's not it.
違う？
Wrong?
ランプ、グリーン。コード4本。
The lamp is green. Four wires.
あ、レッドだから左から3番目？
Ah, it's red, so the third one from the left?
あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。オッケーです。
Ah, okay, okay. It's fine.
じゃあ、次はえっと、レバーいきます。
Then next is the levers.
はい。
Okay.
レバーが、え、左からいきます。えっと、一番右のやつね。一番右のやつ。
Levers, starting from the left... I mean, the rightmost one.
はい。
Okay.
えっと、グリーン、下。
Uh, green, down.
イエロー、下。
Yellow, down.
レッド、下。
Red, down.
ブルー、下。
Blue, down.
おお。
Oh.
オッケー。じゃ、次いきます。次が、十字の真ん中に点字があるやついきます。
Okay. Moving on. Next is the cross with braille in the middle.
右下いきますよ。ランプがレッドです。
Going to the bottom right. The lamp is red.
数字が？
What's the number?
6。
6.
数字6です。上。
The number is 6. Up.
オッケー。次、ランプが、え、グリーン。
Okay. Next, the lamp is green.
えっと、点字が...
Uh, the braille is...
点字が9？
The braille is 9?
えっと、これ右だっけ？右？
Uh, is this one right?
あ、違う。左だっけ？左。
Ah, no. Left? Left.
あ、ごめん、私の伝え方が、あれでした。えっと、ランプがレッド。
Ah, sorry, I didn't explain that well. Uh, the lamp is red.
返事が ええと 4です
The response is... uh, 4.
返事は？
The response?
4 4 4
返子が4 上
The response is 4, Up.
えー 次がランプがブルー
Uh, next, the lamp is blue.
返子が3 上
The response is 3, Up.
次がええと ランプがグリーン
Next is, uh, the lamp is green.
返子が 4
The response is 4.
えーと 左だっけ？左
Uh, was it left? Left.
左ですか？本当に左ですか？
Left? Are you sure it's left?
OK OK OK
Okay, okay, okay.
ランプがイエロー
The lamp is yellow.
返子が2
The response is 2.
左
Left.
OK 次がええと 左下の計算のやつです
Okay, next is, uh, the math puzzle in the bottom-left.
57引く3だから
57 minus 3, so...
よ 54？
5... 54?
合ってるか？
Is that right?
54？54ですか？
54? Is it 54?
5 4
で ええと ランプがグリーン
And, uh, the lamp is green.
え 9
Uh, 9.
あ！ OK！
Ah! Okay!
おー うまい うまい
Ohhh, nice, nice!
偶数か奇数かわからんかった
I didn't know if it was even or odd!
フブちゃんだったんだ
It was Fubu-chan.
そう そう そう 何だっけ？あの even numberだっけ？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. What was it? "Even number", right?
odd number even number what? みたいな感じ
It was like, "Odd number? Even number? What?!"
左と右を間違えております
Confusing left and right.
odd number or even number what? って
"Odd number or even number? What?!"
どっちだ？みたいな
Like, "Which one is it?!"
やばい 数字やばかった
Man, those numbers were crazy.
でも いけましたよ
But we got it!
左、右とかで伝えて、ちゃんと伝わって、ありがとね
Thanks for conveying it with left and right so it got through.
絶対こっちは混乱するやつ
That's definitely the type to cause confusion.
いや、私もよくあれです、あの、FF14やったとき
Actually, I often do that. When playing FFXIV...
タンクさんが「左」って言ったら、「え？私の左？君の左？」って言って死んで
the tank says "left", and I ask "My left or your left?" and die...
どっち？どっちなの？どっちの左！？って
"Which one? Which one is it?! Which left?!"
パニクってわからなくなる
You panic and lose track.
まだありますので、次はレベル8いきましょう
We still have more, so let's move on to level 8.
はーい
Okay!
あ、聞こえない
Ah, I can't hear anything.
お、新しいやつがあります
Oh, there's a new module.
ええと、シンボルが4つあって
Uh, there are four symbols...
そうなんです、シンボルがあって
Yes, there are symbols...
あの、右に、あのスクウェアのボタンが3つある
And to the right, there are three square buttons.
あのスクウェアのボタンは、上から緑、赤、バナナです
Those square buttons are, from top to bottom: green, red, banana.
で、シンボルは
And the symbols...
ええと、時計の12時だったら、あのスクウェアの中に、あの丸い、です
Uh, at 12 o'clock, there's a circle inside a square.
で、
And...
ど、どうすればいいこれ？やったことないから
W-What should I do here? I've never done this before.
上？
Up?
ん？ボタンを
Hmm? The button...
クリックした方がいいか？
Should I click it?
え、いや、違う、違う
Uh, wait, no, that's not it.
ええ、ローテイト？あ、回る、回すの？
Uh, rotate? Ah, turn it? Do I spin it?
はい
Yes.
どこで回せばいいんですか？
Where should I turn it?
ええと、あ、12時は、あのスクウェアと丸いサークル
Uh, ah, 12 o'clock is the square and circle.
で、3時は、あの星。あの、中がない星
And 3 o'clock is a star. An outlined star with no filling.
で、6時が、あ、あれですか？あの、線の星、合ってますか？
And 6 o'clock is, oh, is it that one? The star made of lines. Is that correct?
で、あの、ボタンをポチッとした方がいいですか？何を...
And, should I click the button? What...
あ、イエロー？
Ah, yellow?
あーと、次の、あの、一番下のボタンをクリックしてください。あ、いやいやいや
Uh, next, please click the bottom-most button. Ah, no no no!
あ、はい、はい
Ah, yes, yes.
あ、間違えた
Ah, I made a mistake!
え、じゃ、シンボルもう一回言いますね
Uh, then, I'll say the symbols one more time.
12時はスクウェアとサークル、ええと、3時は
12 o'clock is square and circle, uh, 3 o'clock is...
線の星、6時が全部ある星、で、ええと
the star with lines, 6 o'clock is the filled star, and, uh...
9時が、ええ、何の砂の、あれ。で、ええと、ボタンが
9 o'clock is, uh, something like sand. And, uh, the button is...
の、色は、上から、赤...
The colors from the top are: red...
えー、黄色、緑です。
...uh, yellow, green.
で、えー、口、口、合ってますか？
And, uh, the mouth, is the mouth correct?
オッケー。え、はい、はい、はい、はい。で、色のボタン、えー
Okay. Uh, yes, yes, yes, yes. And, the colored button, uh...
どの色のボタン？
Which color button?
えっと、赤、バナナ、緑。
Um, red, banana, green.
バナナ？
Banana?
え？
Huh?
赤かな？赤ですか？
Maybe red? Is it red?
違う？
No?
赤？
Red?
違う。えー、バナナ？
No. Uh, banana?
あ、緑！
Ah, green!
えっと、一番下のボタンです。はい。
Um, it's the bottommost button. Yes.
あ、もう一回。オッケー、オッケー。
Ah, one more time. Okay, okay.
え、これ、え？え？え？
Eh, this, eh? Eh? Eh?
えっと、えっと
Um, um...
シンボルは同じく上から、緑、赤、黄色です。
The symbols are similarly, from the top: green, red, yellow.
そっか。
I see.
いや、難しい、これ！
Wow, this is hard!
あとね、さっきのが、フレアが、モジュールを回して、ダイヤルを。
Also, for the previous one, Flare was turning the module's dial.
で、記号があったじゃん？記号が。
And there were symbols, right?
音が鳴る箇所があるんだよね。
There's a spot where it makes a sound.
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that so?
ダイヤルを回すと、
When you turn the dial,
記号のところで多分音が鳴る。その音が鳴ったところの記号を教えて欲しかったんだよね。
it probably makes a sound at the symbol. I wanted you to tell me that symbol.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
星二つあるから、どうやって伝えようかね？これ。
Since there are two stars, how should we communicate them?
線の星。
The lined star.
普通の星、線の星。
Normal star, lined star.
普通の星って言う時は普通の星だと思って、線の時は線の星って言うか。
When saying normal star, assume it's normal, and for the other, say "lined star."
いや、これは難しいな、伝えるの。
Wow, this is hard to explain.
音が鳴ったところで止まって、
Stop at the place where the sound plays,
その色のボタン、ですかね？
and press that colored button?
そうそうそう。
Exactly, yeah.
音が鳴ったところを教えてもらえたら教えられたね、色が。
If you told me where the sound played, I could have told you the color.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうそう、ボタンを押すっていうのね。
Right, right, pushing the button.
いや、これはやばいな。
Wow, this is crazy.
あー。
Ah.
なんか、カチみたいな音がしたやつは一個あったから、多分そういうことだよね？それを教えるってことだよね？
There was one that made a click-like sound, so that must be it, right? Telling that?
そうそうそうそう。じゃあ、ちょっと行ってみるか。
Exactly, exactly. Let's give it a try.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
伝える時、あ。
When explaining... Ah.
はい。
Yes.
あ、え、と。さっきのやつで、
Ah, um, with the previous one...
上が、えっと、線の星。
The top one is, um, the lined star.
一番右の、その星、
The one on the far right, that star...
下が、砂時計。左が、普通の星。
The bottom is the hourglass. The left is the normal star.
えっと、あの、スクエア、サークルです。
Um, that... square, circle.
で、ランプが上から、赤、黄色、緑。
And the lamps from the top are: red, yellow, green.
あの、音が出たのがスクエアとサークルです。
Um, the ones that made a sound are square and circle.
あ、今言わなかったやつね。
Ah, the ones you didn't say just now.
右のやつ。えっと、黄色、真ん中のランプ。
The right one. Um, yellow, the middle lamp.
オッケー。
Okay.
で、次が
And next is...
えっと、形は一緒で、ランプが緑、黄色、赤。
Um, the shapes are the same, and the lamps are green, yellow, red.
で、カチっていう音が、えっと、
And the clicking sound is, um...
普通の星でいいのかな？線の星で合ってる？
Is it the normal star? Is it the lined star?
うん。線の星です。線の星。
Yeah, it's the lined star. Lined star.
線の星です。
It's the lined star.
あと赤だから一番下のランプ。
And it's red, so the bottom lamp.
はい。
Yes.
オッケー。
Okay.
えっと、砂時計かな？
The hourglass?
で、次が
And next is...
また砂時計、あ、どっちもこれ砂時計な、下の砂時計だから、
Another hourglass, ah, both of these are hourglasses, the bottom hourglass, so...
ランプが赤、緑、黄色。
the lamps are red, green, yellow.
a, kiiro. kiiro. etto, ranpu ga ichiban shita.
Ah, yellow. Yellow. Um, the lamp at the bottom.
あ、あれ？違った。
Ah, wait, that was wrong.
違ったらしいです。
Seems like it was wrong.
次行きます。
Moving on.
えっと、砂時計のマークで、ランプが緑、黄色、赤です。
Um, with the hourglass mark, the lamps are green, yellow, red.
砂時計。
Hourglass.
き、黄色。
Ye- Yellow.
えー、ってことは、えっと真ん中のランプです。
Uh, which means, the middle lamp.
オッケー。
Okay.
次が、えっと、
Next is, um...
あ、線の星です。
Ah, the lined star.
線の星で、ランプが赤、緑、黄色。
Lined star, lamps are red, green, yellow.
えっと、赤だから一番上です。
Um, it's red, so the top one.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
あ、砂時計です。
Ah, it's the hourglass.
次が、また砂時計、あ、どっちもこれ砂時計な、下の砂時計だから、
Next is another hourglass, ah, both of these are hourglasses, the bottom hourglass, so...
三角二つの砂時計 上と下で三角二つのやつ
The hourglass with two triangles, one on top and one on bottom...
ランプが緑 赤 黄色です 順番が
...and the lamps are green, red, and yellow, in order...
上からね 一番上のランプお願いします
...from the top. The top lamp, please!
はい ナイス
Yes! Nice!
え えっと square と circle
Um, next is... square and circle?
なんかよく分かんないデザインのやつのやつと
Some design I don't really understand, and...
ランプがえ 黄色 緑 赤
...the lamps are yellow, green, and red.
え 真ん中の...あ 違う え？赤？
Um, the middle... oh wait, what? Red?
赤だって 赤だから一番下 右下です
It says red. Red, so the very bottom, bottom right.
あ オッケー おお
Ah, okay! Oh!
おお ナイス ナイス
Oh, nice, nice!
右下にあるから なんかよく分かんねえデザインだけど
It's in the bottom right, so even though it's a weird design...
何にも見えなかった うわー！
...I couldn't see anything at all! Whoa!
なんも分からんと思ったけど
I thought I wouldn't understand anything!
砂時計 助かった 三角の砂時計 助かった
The hourglass saved me! The triangle hourglass saved me!
なんか右のやつ分かんないと思ったけど 三角しかねえ
I thought I wouldn't know the right one, but there's only triangles!
砂時計も二つあったんだ じゃあ
So there were two hourglasses, then?
あ そう そうそう あったんですか？
Ah, yes, yes yes! Were there?
そうそうそう なんかね 三角と なんか丸みたいな砂時計
Yes yes yes, like a triangle one and a circle-like hourglass.
あ そういうことだったんだ
Ah, so that's what it was.
そう じゃあ次行こう レベル９！
Yes! Well, let's go to the next. Level 9!
おお！
Oh!
よし 次のモジュールだ マニュアル
Alright, next module. The manual!
何から行こうかな？
What should we start with?
え とりあえず 左上から行こうか？
Um, for now, should we go from the top left?
あ オッケー 左上
Ah, okay. Top left.
左上は？
What is top left?
えっとね えっと 丸に四角の...
Um, let's see... a circle with a square...
丸の中にえ 四角が入ってるやつ
...with a square inside the circle.
で ランプが 黄色 緑 赤です 上からね
And the lamps are yellow, green, and red from the top.
丸の中に四角 丸の中に四角が入ってる
A square in a circle. There's a square inside a circle.
あ あ wait it's the symbols. Okay, okay, okay.
Oh, oh, wait! It's the symbols. Okay, okay, okay.
記号が 丸の中に四角
The symbol is a square inside a circle.
はい で
Yes. And...
丸の中に四角... え？
...a square inside a circle... Huh?
あ あ これか なるほどね あ
Oh, oh, this one? I see. Ah.
わかったら わかったら 丸の中に四角 わかったら
Tell me when you got it, the square inside the circle.
え 黄色 黄色 黄色だから一番上のランプをお願いします
Um, yellow, yellow. Since it's yellow, the top-most lamp, please.
４回目ってのがあって ４回しなきゃいけなくて 今１回目の...
There are 4 stages, we have to do it 4 times. Right now is the 1st...
えっと 丸の中の四角
...um, the square inside the circle.
はい 左上 一番上のランプを押してください
Yes, top left. Please press the top-most lamp.
はい あれ？ あ 違う
Okay. Huh? Ah, wrong.
ちゃうんか
Was it wrong?
次が １回目の... えっと 三角
Next is... um, a triangle...
三角に なんかラインが入ってる 上に
A triangle with some line in it on top.
三角に... はい はい はい
On the triangle... Yes, yes, yes.
えー なんだこれ？
Um, what is this?
トライアングルになんか横棒が入ってる
A horizontal bar inside the triangle.
三角に 上のほうに斜線がピッて入ってるやつで
A triangle with a diagonal line at the top, and...
ランプが 赤 緑 黄色
...the lamps are red, green, and yellow.
赤 緑 黄色 ランプの色かな？
Red, green, yellow. Is that the lamp color?
教えて 教えて １
Tell me, tell me. 1.
１ 三角の上のほうに一本線が入ってる
1. There is a line on the top part of the triangle.
緑 緑 緑 緑
Green, green, green, green.
え 緑だから 真ん中のランプです
Um, since it's green, it's the middle lamp.
オッケー！ ナイス！
Okay! Nice!
オッケー オッケー オッケー ナイス
Okay, okay, okay. Nice.
で次が さっきと同じ丸の中にえ 四角が 入ってて
And next is the same as before, a square inside a circle, and...
丸 丸ってなんて言ったらいい...
Circle... how should I say...
ランプがえ 黄色 緑 赤です
...the lamps are yellow, green, and red.
黄色 丸ってなんて伝えたらいいんだ？
Yellow. How should I describe the circle?
It's O, right? あ なななかな？
It's an "O", right? Or "nana" maybe?
え 黄色だから 一番上
Um, since it's yellow, the top-most.
オッケー！ ２回目ね ３回目 オッケー
Okay! The 2nd time. The 3rd time, okay.
え 次また三角に横棒
Um, next is again, the triangle with the horizontal bar.
次が また三角 普通の三角に 上に一本線が入ってるやつで
Next is a triangle again, a normal triangle with a line on top, and...
ラインがある そう
There is a line. Yes.
ランプが グリーン レッド イエローです
...the lamps are green, red, and yellow.
グリーン レッド イエロー ラウンド３
Green, red, yellow. Round 3.
え えっと 赤 赤 赤 赤 赤 赤 赤
Um, let's see... red, red, red, red. Red, red, red.
えっと 赤だから 真ん中のランプです
Um, since it's red, it's the middle lamp.
オッケー 次ラスト ラウンド４！
Okay, next is last! Round 4!
ラスト！
Last!
えっと square と circle
Um, square and circle.
次が え 四角 四角の中に丸の デザインで
Next is a square. A circle inside a square design, and...
square in circle. 丸と四角
Square in circle. Circle and square.
ランプが 赤 グリーン 黄色です
...the lamps are red, green, and yellow.
え 赤
Um, red.
え 一 一番上のランプでお願いします
Um, the top-most lamp, please.
ナイス！ オッケー オッケー オッケー オッケー
Nice! Okay, okay, okay, okay.
次は えっと 計算... これ計算見えない 55 + 2 かな？
Next is, um, math... I can't see the math. Is it 55 + 2?
55 + 2
だから な 57 57 55 55 55 55...
So, s- 57. 57, 55, 55, 55, 55...
あれ？ 奇数だから
Huh? Since it's odd...
ランプの色は？
What's the lamp color?
ランプ  ランプ ランプ ランプ ランプの色は？
Lamp, lamp, lamp, lamp, what's the lamp color?
ランプ  ランプ ランプ ランプの色！
Lamp, lamp, lamp, lamp color!
あ ランプ ごめん レッド レッド レッド レッド！
Oh, the lamp, sorry! Red, red, red, red!
レッド えー... オッケー オッケー
Red, um... Okay, okay.
なんだっけ あの 57？ 57？
What was it, um, 57? 57?
ですか？
Is it?
あー！ ごめん  ランプの色忘れてた 私
Ah! Sorry, I forgot the lamp color.
ごめん ごめん ごめん
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
ゴリラを叩くしかなかった
I had no choice but to slam the gorilla!
ランプの色 完全に忘れてた ごめん
I completely forgot the lamp color, sorry.
ううん 全然 全然大丈夫です
No no, it's totally, totally fine.
聞こえてただろうな
They probably heard that.
伝わらなかった。ごめん、ごめん。
It didn't get across. Sorry, sorry.
いろんなものをあの...
There were various things...
色、色、色って...
Like color, color, color...
テレパシーが... いやいやいや、大丈夫です。大丈夫です。
Telepathy... No, no, it's fine. It's fine.
次、次行ってみよう。
Let's move on to the next one.
はい、えーと、えーと、えーと...
Okay, let's see...
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。行きます。えーと...
Okay, okay, okay. Here I go.
コード！カラーコード4本です。
Wires! There are four color wires.
これ、フレアか？イナか？イナ？
Is this Flare? Or Ina? Ina?
あ、フレア、フレアか。あ、イナ、オッケー。
Oh, it's Flare. Ah, Ina, okay.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。イナ！
Okay, okay, okay. Ina!
えーと、そのボタンモニターの右の...
So, to the right of the button monitor...
やつは、そうそう、その9個のモニターはランプが光ったら押してください。
Yeah, for those nine monitors, press them
when the lamp lights up.
コードは4本で、色は黄色。
There are four wires, and the color is yellow.
はい。
Got it.
あ、色は黄色。うんうん、オッケー、オッケー。
Oh, the color is yellow. Yeah, okay, okay.
4本で黄色。イエロー。
Four wires and yellow. Yellow.
何、何色切ればいい？
Which color should I cut?
ここに、赤？赤か？
Red here? Is it red?
赤じゃない。緑？
Not red. Green?
青？青、青、青って。
Blue? Blue, blue, blue.
イナ、えーと、右から2番目かな？
Ina, maybe the second one from the right?
右から2番目？はい。
Second from the right? Okay.
オッケー。で、次が記号です。記号。
Okay. Next are the symbols. Symbols.
一番右にあるかな？オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
The one on the far right? Okay, okay, okay.
線の星です。
It's the star outline.
えーと、音が鳴るのを教えてほしいです。音が鳴るのを。
Let me know which one makes a sound.
線の星です。
The star outline.
あ、それオッケー？
Oh, that's done?
こう、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Like this. Okay, okay, okay.
えーと、音が鳴るのが星。
Let's see, the star makes a sound.
線の星。
The star outline.
で、記号なんだけど、1、2、3、4って横にあって、
As for the symbols, they are lined up
1, 2, 3, 4 horizontally.
まず1回目の、えーと、線の星。
First, the first star outline.
塗られてない星。
The unshaded star.
の色は、何色？
What color is it?
1個目の線だけの星は、
The first star outline...
赤、緑、黄色、どれが対応してるかな？
Is it mapped to red, green, or yellow?
イエローだから、1番目かな？
It's yellow, so the first one?
あ。
Oh.
No! No! No!
No?
また、また線の... 線の星です。
Again, it's the star... the star outline.
オッケー、もう一回、えーと、さっきの線の星。
Okay, once more. The star outline from earlier.
1番目の線の星。
The first star outline.
1番目の線の星、はい。
The first star outline, yes.
緑。
Green.
緑だから、一番下かな？
Since it's green, is it the bottom one?
はい、はい。オッケー、で、次。
Yes, yes. Okay, next.
あ。
Ah.
えーと。
Let's see.
逆三角に下に線が入ってる。
An inverted triangle with a line at the bottom.
逆三角で横ラインが入ってて、2回目。
An inverted triangle with a horizontal line.
The second one.
緑？
Green?
オッケー、緑だから一番上。
Okay, it's green, so the top one.
はい。
Got it.
ナイス。
Nice.
線の星です。
It's the star outline.
線の星、3回目。
The star outline, third one.
3。
Three.
何色？
What color?
見えない。
I can't see it.
あ、黄色、真ん中。
Ah, yellow, the middle one.
あ、真ん中。オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Ah, the middle one. Okay, okay, okay.
オッケー、ラスト。
Okay, last one.
えーと、四角の中になる。
Let's see, it's inside the square.
4回目、四角。
Fourth one, the square.
何色？
What color?
はい？ノイキャンが...
What? The noise canceler...
ノイキャン...
The noise canceler...
上。
Top.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
ノイキャンが、
The noise canceler...
ノイキャンがすごいの。
The noise canceler is so strong.
あ、ノイキャンが、全然聞こえんかった。
Ah, the noise canceler... I couldn't hear
you at all.
やばい、ノイキャン...
Oh no, the noise canceler...
まさかノイキャンが敵とは。
Who would've thought the noise canceler
was the enemy?
やばいね。高い声出すとやばいね、ノイキャン。
It's bad. When I raise my voice,
the noise canceler goes crazy.
でも、できましたよ。
But we did it.
あ、よかった、よかった。ナイス。
Oh, thank goodness. Nice.
上手い、上手い。
Good job, good job.
上手すぎる。じゃ、ちょっと次、
Too good! Let's do the next one.
記号がパニクるね、これ。
The symbols make you panic, don't they?
ね。
Right?
じゃ、次、レベル10。
Okay, next, Level 10.
これなら、みんな
If so, everyone...
みんなこの、お口塞いでるやつにしてみて。ミュート。
Everyone try setting it to the one
covering the mouth. Mute.
あ、全員ミュート？
Oh, everyone is muted?
ミュート。これで、
Mute. With this...
こうすると、変わるかな？
If we do this, will it change?
あ。
Oh.
え、全然、全然変わってな...
Wait, it hasn't changed at all...
全然変わってない。喋れないわけじゃない。
Not at all. It doesn't mean we can't talk.
えーと...
Let's see...
どっちから行こうかな。レバーから行きます。
Which one should we do first?
Let's start with the levers.
レバー、オッケー、オッケー。
Levers, okay, okay.
えーと、レバーが、左から行きます。赤。
Let's see. Levers, starting from the left. Red.
上。
Up.
はい。
Got it.
緑。
Green.
上。
Up.
青。
Blue.
上。
Up.
黄色。
Yellow.
下。
Down.
はい、はい、はい。よい、よい。
Got it, got it. Perfect, perfect.
次が、えーと、記号のやつ行きます。
Next, let's do the symbols.
左上行きます。
Going for the top left.
音が出るやつは、丸に縦線みたいな入ってるやつ。
The one making a sound is the circle
with a vertical line in it.
で、ランプが、ランプは別に向き...
And the lamp... well, the lamp's direction...
うん。
Yeah.
ランプが、赤緑黄色だけど、
The lamp is red, green, yellow, but...
1回目の...
The first one's...
はい。一番上？
Yes. The very top?
一番上のランプ。
The topmost lamp.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
音が出るやつ、次が、えーと、線の星です。
The one that makes a sound... next is, uh, the lined star.
線の星。
The lined star.
赤が、真ん中です。
The red is the middle.
真ん中、オッケー。
Middle, okay.
あ、次、音が出るのは、
Ah, next, the one that makes a sound is...
三角、あ、違う、えーと、砂時計...
Triangle... no, wait, hourglass...
丸い、うん、丸い砂時計。
The round... yeah, the round hourglass.
半円みたいなやつの砂時計で、えーと、右下、一番下のランプです。
The hourglass that looks like a semicircle... and, uh, bottom-right, the bottommost lamp.
オッケー。
Okay.
あ、次が...
Ah, next is...
えー、再び丸に縦線入ってるやつ、
Uh, the one with a vertical line in a circle again...
が、えーと、み、一番下のランプです。
is, uh, the... bottommost lamp.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
次が、えーと、点字のやつに十、十字ついてるやつ。
Next is, uh, the braille one with a cross on it.
で、ランプが青です。
And the lamp is blue.
えー、番号は2です。2です。
Uh, the number is 2. It's 2.
点字いくら？
What's the braille number?
2です。
It's 2.
えー、点字が2です。
Uh, the braille is 2.
ランプが青です。
The lamp is blue.
上。
Up.
あ、違う。あ、違う？
Ah, wait, no. Ah, no?
えーと、次いきます。えーと、ランプが、あ、なんか、こう、こうなった。
Uh, going to the next. Uh, the lamp... ah, something... it went like this.
ランプが赤、1。で、点字が1。
The lamp is red, 1. And the braille is 1.
上。
Up.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
で、で、ランプが黄色...
And, and, the lamp is yellow...
え、で、これが、7です。
Eh, and this is 7.
点字が、7です。
The braille is 7.
えーと、左だっけ？これ。
Uh, was it left? This.
左。
Left.
左ですか？左ですか？
Left? Left?
オッケー。
Okay.
で、次が、ランプが赤。
And next, the lamp is red.
8。
8.
点字が8。
The braille is 8.
上。
Up.
オッケー。
Okay.
で、次がランプが黄色。
And next, the lamp is yellow.
あ。
Ah.
えーと、これが、3。
Uh, this is 3.
で、えーと、点字が3。ランプが黄色。あ、上。
And, uh, the braille is 3. The lamp is yellow. Ah, up.
あー！
Ah!
おおー。
Ooh.
なのー。
Nano.
いいですね。
That's good.
なんかさ、け、計算してんの？あの、で、電卓みたいなやつって。な、何してんの？あれ。
Like, are you calculating? That calculator-looking thing. What are you doing with that?
うん。
Yeah.
ランプが光ったら押す。
When the lamp lights up, press it.
え、ここのランプの、場所を押せ、みたいな感じ？
Wait, like, press the location of the lamp here?
そうそうそう。
Yes, yes, yes.
あー、なるほどね。なんか、ミニの数字出てきてないから、な、何を押してんのかなと思って。
Ah, I see. Since no mini-numbers were showing, I was wondering what you were pressing.
あ、なんか、なんか、ピピピピしてたから、あの、その、光るんですよ。なんか。
Ah, it was like making beeping sounds, so... it lights up. Somehow.
そう、光るんだよ。
Yeah, it lights up.
お、光ったとこ押せばいいんだ。
Oh, so you just need to press the lit part.
そうそうそう。制限時間内に。
Yes, yes, yes. Within the time limit.
はい。
Yes.
そう。
Yeah.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
あ、な、何？誰だこれ？誰だ？誰だ？いいのか？あ、いいのだいいのだ。オッケーオッケー。
Ah, wh-what? Who is this? Who? Who? Is it okay? Ah, it's fine, it's fine. Okay, okay.
あ、ピアノモジュール！やった！
Ah, piano module! Yay!
あ、新しい。
Ah, a new one.
ピアノ。
Piano.
ランプがグリーン。
The lamp is green.
え、なんか、何すればいいの？どこ押せばいいの？
Eh, like, what should I do? Where should I press?
ちょ、やばいぞ、これ！
Wait, this is bad!
なになに、何ですか？
What, what, what is it?
ピアノモジュールやばい。
The piano module is bad.
あ、ピアノか。
Ah, piano?
ランプ、ランプがグリーンで、
The lamp, the lamp is green,
また点字があって、点々。で、たぶん、番号が、あ！おっぱ...
and there's braille again, dots. And, probably, the number is... Ah! Oppa...
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
グリーンの、グリーンの？グリーン？
Green, green? Green?
グリーン！うん、イエス、グリーン。グリーン、グリーン。
Green! Yeah, yes, green. Green, green.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
えー、ピアノで、グリーン。
Uh, piano, and green.
1？
1?
1？1だって。
1? They said 1.
なになになに！
What, what, what!
えーと、え？まだずっとランプ、グリーンだよ。
Uh, eh? The lamp is still green.
これ、5、5なのをさ、
This is 5, it's 5...
2回目ね。2回目のランプがグリーン。
The second time. The second lamp is green.
あらはら。
Oh my.
5はどう、どう伝えたらいいんだろう。
How, how should I convey 5?
5ですか？5？
Is it 5? 5?
ランプ、グリーンだよ。
The lamp is green.
あ、喋らないか。5？
Ah, don't talk? 5?
おっぱーわ。ランプ、グリーン。
Oppah-wa. Lamp, green.
5！
5!
5！5！
5! 5!
のー！
No!
のー、クエスチョン。
No, question.
違う、のー。違う、5じゃない。
No, wait, no. No, it's not 5.
5ですか？
Is it 5?
あ、でも、ランプついてるよ。合ってんじゃない？
Ah, but the lamp is lit. Isn't it right?
あ、合ってますか？
Ah, is it right?
合ってた、合ってた、合ってた。5で合ってた。
It was right, it was right, it was right. It was right with 5.
次が、またグリーンだ。
Next is green again.
はい、グリーンで、
Yes, green, and...
グリーン？
Green?
全部5だもんね。
It's all 5, right?
グリーンで、
Green, and...
なんだ次。3回目のグリーン。
What's next? The third green.
3回目のグリーン？
The third green?
え？
Eh?
フブキさん何見てるんですか？
Fubuki-san, what are you looking at?
あ、喋らない！
Ah, don't talk!
いいな！いいな！
So nice! So nice!
え？な、なん、何？
Eh? Wh-Wh-What?
C, D, E, F, G, A, B。この、数字関係あるかな？
C, D, E, F, G, A, B. Does this number have something to do with it?
あー！
Ah!
惜しいのか。
Is it close?
なんか、音が聞こえるぞ。
I can hear a sound.
聞こえるんだ。
You can hear it.
グリーンの何ですか？
Green... what is it?
グリーンの、何？
Green... what?
Ah, based on the octave number written in Braille...
グリーン・ランプ、ランプはグリーン。
Green lamp, the lamp is green.
で、2回目ってことなのかな？関係ないのかな？
So does that mean the second time? Or does it not matter?
What is octave number...
お姉さんが教えてあげなきゃいけないのかも。その、鍵盤の数字なのか、英語なのか。
Maybe I have to teach you. Like, is it piano key numbers, or English?
何？５？５って書いてあるよ、５。
What? 5? It says 5, 5.
ずっと？ ずっと５なんだけど。
Always? It's always 5 though.
I have to see... ランプはグリーンで、
I have to see... The lamp is green, and...
C-C, G-C-G-C-G... 数字なのか、英語なのか。
C-C, G-C-G-C-G... Is it numbers, or English?
So, it's two... 何？これ。
So, it's two... What is this?
C, D, E, F, G, A, B... これ、ナンバー？
C, D, E, F, G, A, B... Is this a number?
これ、どう、どうしたらいい？C-D-E-F... F-G-A-B, どっちだ？パペット、パペットわかんない。
What should I do with this? C-D-E-F... F-G-A-B, which one? I don't get the puppet.
Oh, C-D-E-F-G-A-B... なんか聞こえる。
Oh, C-D-E-F-G-A-B... I hear something.
All of them is C? 全部５だけど。C５...
All of them is C? They're all 5, though. C5...
Green, so it's C, G, C, G, right? C5, G5, E5, G5, E5, D5, G5...みたいな。
Green, so it's C, G, C, G, right? Like C5, G5, E5, G5, E5, D5, G5...
1-5-1-5? One... 何回目です。１？１だって、１。
1-5-1-5? One... Which turn is it? 1? It says 1, 1.
１って教えてもらってるよ、１。あ、お、通った！通った！
They're telling me 1, 1. Ah, oh, it went through! It went through!
もう１回、もう１回！
One more time, one more time!
グリーン！５！５だって！ C, D...
Green! 5! It says 5! C, D...
Is it all... All of them is 5. 1-2-3-4... え？全部、全部なら、５。1, 2, 3...
Is it all... All of them is 5. 1-2-3-4... Eh? If it's all, all of them, it's 5. 1, 2, 3...
わー！できた、できた！
Wah! We did it, we did it!
え？これ私、イナに伝える物ってなんだった？
Eh? What was I supposed to tell Ina?
あの、上に、あの、ランプの色があって、
Um, on top, there are lamp colors,
左のコラムは、あの、ナンバーでした。
and the left column was, um, numbers.
で、５、５があって、それをマッチしたら、
And there was a 5, 5, and if I matched that,
あの、ノートがあったんですよ、なんかC-G-C-Gとか。 あ、あ、あ、なるほど、ふんふん。
there were notes, like C-G-C-G or something. Ah, ah, ah, I see, I see.
で、あれを、あの、ピアノでプレイするとクリア。 あ、そうだったのかな？
And playing that on the piano clears it. Ah, was that it?
なんかイナに教えてもらった番号は全部合ってた。
Somehow, all the numbers Ina told me were correct.
なんとなくそうだったんだね。C5, D5, B5みたいになってたけど、全部なんか変わ...
So that's how it was. It was like C5, D5, B5, but it all seemed to...
同じだったんだよね、鍵盤の数字とアルファベット。 ふんふんふんふん。
They were the same, the piano key numbers and alphabets. Hmm, hmm, hmm, hmm.
なんか、あの、正解だったのが、C-G-C-Gだったから、
Since, um, the correct answer was C-G-C-G,
なんか、1-5-1-5、
it was like, 1-5-1-5,
だったかな、左から？ なるほどね。
from the left? I see.
で、なんとなく、1-5-1-5入れて、クリアした。
So I just put in 1-5-1-5 and cleared it.
1-5と1-5だったんだ。でも合ってたからオッケーや！新しいモジュールがやばいな、次も行こう！
So it was 1-5 and 1-5. Well, it was correct, so it's okay! The new module is crazy. Let's go to the next one!
Ah, results... 結果は出ない。
Ah, results... The results won't show.
Ah, Kekka wa denai.
Ah, results won't show.
えっと、計算かな、あの、左上の、
Um, is it math, the top-left one...
55マイナス15は、え、40。
55 minus 15 is... um, 40.
はい、あとランプは青で、40です。
Okay, and the lamp is blue, it's 40.
いいんかな？
Is it okay?
1。
1.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。で、あ、ピアノ来ました。
Okay, okay, okay. And, oh, the piano is here.
ピアノのランプは赤です。
The piano lamp is red.
あのチャート難しいですからね。
Because that chart is difficult.
えっと、6。
Um, 6.
あ、間違えた。えっと、ランプの色が赤です。
Ah, I made a mistake. Um, the lamp color is red.
えー、6。
Uh, 6.
番号は6。赤いランプで6。
The number is 6. 6 with a red lamp.
オッケー。
Okay.
赤いランプの6。
6 on the red lamp.
5、左から5。
5, 5 from the left.
あ、オッケー、オッケー、オッケーです。あ、できたかな？
Ah, okay, okay, it's okay. Ah, is it done?
左から5。4。
5 from the left. 4.
オッケーです。あ、また赤...
It's okay. Ah, red again...
おねがいします
Please.
Three.
はい
Yes.
Two.
おわあ！
Woah!
これ、フブちゃんに私の声聞こえてるんだよね？
Fubu-chan, you can hear my voice, right?
そう、聞こえてるんだけど、これ、あれだ、あの、音階じゃなくて、あの、C, D, Eで教えてあげなきゃいけないんだよね
Yes, I can hear you, but for this, we shouldn't use the solfege names, we have to teach it using C, D, E.
たぶん
Probably.
音階のC, D, E, F, G, A...だっけ？ 忘れちゃったけど、それの
The musical scale C, D, E, F, G, A... was it? I forgot, but for that...
あの、Cだったら、Cで1番目だから、1を教えてあげるみたいな感じだったんだよね
Like, if it's C, since C is the first, you tell them to press "1" sort of thing.
あー、なるほど
Ah, I see.
そう、これ、音階分かってないと
Right, if you don't know the scale...
これ、これピアノ知らなかった方は無理じゃない？なるほど。
For someone who doesn't know the piano, isn't this impossible? I see.
そう、ねー
Right?
私はギリギリどこがCだっけ？
For me, I was barely like, "Wait, where is C?"
はいはいはい。あれだね、C, D, E, F, G, A, B かな？
I see. It's C, D, E, F, G, A, B, right?
そう、そう、そう
Yes, yes, yes.
伝える時にCって言えないから難しいんだ
It's hard because you can't say "C" when communicating.
ね、難しいよね。でもランプと番号さえ分かったら、全然いけたね、今のはね
Yeah, it's hard. But if you know the light and the number, it's totally doable, like just now.
はい、なるほど
Yes, I see.
ピアノ難しい
Piano is hard.
じゃ、最初にあの、C, D, Eって言って
So, if you say "C, D, E" at the start,
何番目かを把握してもらうのがいいのかな？ちょっとお手洗い行ってもいいですか？
and have them figure out which number it is, maybe? Can I go to the restroom quickly?
いってらっしゃい
Go ahead!
はーい
Okay!
いや、ピアノが...
Man, the piano...
ピアノが難しくて思い出せなかった、ピアノを一瞬
The piano was so hard, I couldn't remember it for a second.
そうですね、ねー
Indeed.
それ合ってますね、なんかCが1で、Dが2で、はいはいはい、おっけおっけ
That's correct. Like, C is 1, D is 2... Yes, yes, yes, okay, okay.
Eが3、Fが4で合ってた
E is 3, F is 4, so it was correct.
あ、ちょっと、あの、チャット、Googleで検索しました、ちょっと
Ah, the chat actually searched on Google for me.
えらいえらい。おぼえてないよ
Good job. I don't remember it.
覚えてないよね。なんでドレミファソラシドじゃないんねん
You wouldn't, right? Why isn't it just Do-Re-Mi-Fa-So-La-Ti-Do?!
困るわ、もう
It's so troubling.
いや、でもこれ面白いな
But this is fun.
いや、でももう、少しずつ慣れているんですよね
But we are getting used to it little by little, aren't we?
ね、もう、だいぶ慣れてきたし、もう新しいのまだあるのかな？どうだろ？
Yeah, we are pretty used to it. Are there still new ones? I wonder.
多分あるかなと。マニュアル、スッと見たらめっちゃありました
Probably. When I glanced at the manual, there were so many.
まだ、まだ、もうちょっとだけあるんじゃ
There's still... still a bit more left.
でも、すごいイナのマニュアルの伝え方がすごい天才すぎて
But Ina's way of explaining the manual is seriously genius.
いやいやいや。なんか知らない単語がありますからね、なんか
No, no, no. There are words I don't know, so...
スク、スクエアサークル
Squa... "Square Circle"!
スクエアサークルってなんだ！
What on earth is a square circle?!
スクエアの中にサークルが
There's a circle inside a square.
そうそうそう、それ、それアンダーライン
Right, right, right, and that... that underlined one.
そうですね
Right.
いや、なんか、サークルはアニメとかでよく使うんですけど
Well, "circle" is often used in anime and stuff...
スクエアはあんまりないんじゃないですか？
But "square" isn't used much, is it?
なかなかにスクエアってなんだっけ？って思ったけど、あれも、あ、なるほど、サークル、スクエア、丸、四角ねって分かりやすかったわ
Indeed, I was like "What was a square again?" but then, "Ah, I see! Circle, square, circle and square!" It was easy to understand.
イナはアニメとかで日本語勉強しましたので、アニメであまり出てない日本語は知らないんですよね
Since I learned Japanese from anime, I don't know Japanese words that don't appear in anime much.
おかえり、おかえりなさい
Welcome back. Welcome back.
いや、サークル、スクエア、でもわかりやすいってなったね
Yeah, "circle, square" was actually very easy to understand.
よかったー、ふぅー
Glad to hear that. Whew.
伝わったらおっけーです
As long as it gets across, it's fine.
丸、四角だね。あの記号のやつね
Circle, square. Those symbol things.
あ、あの記号がめっちゃむずいやつが多すぎて、なんて伝えていいのかわからん
Ah, there are too many super difficult symbols, I don't know how to explain them.
そうですね、助かる
Indeed, that helps.
じゃ、次行ってみるか
Well, shall we go to the next one?
あ、また聞こえない
Ah, I can't hear again.
すっごーい
Amazing.
えっと、どこから行きますか？ピアノから行きます？
Let's see, where should we start? Shall we start with the piano?
いや、いや、なんかイージー、イージーのものから行きましょう wagon
No, let's start with something easy, easy.
えっと、え、スライダー、スライダー
Let's see... the sliders, the sliders.
どうですか？えっと、右下
How are they? Bottom right?
右下、ははは
Bottom right? Haha.
えっと、スライダー左が、え、バナナ
Let's see, the left slider is... a banana.
下？
Down?
下ですか？
Is it down?
下
Down.
えー、1番左のスライダー下です
The leftmost slider is down.
おっけ、えっと、次は緑
Okay, next is green.
下？
Down?
え、2番目も下
The second one is also down.
えっと、赤です
Next is red.
赤も下？
Is red down too?
はい、えっと、3番目も下です
Yes, the third one is also down.
青
Blue.
上です
Up.
おっけおっけおっけ
Okay, okay, okay.
えっと、次は
Let's see, next is...
あの、真ん中で点々点がある
Um, the one in the middle with the dots...
あの、ディレクションボタン、はい
...that direction button. Yes.
えっと、ランプは青です
Uh, the lamp is blue.
で、ナンバーは多分、フブキ先輩...はい
And the number is probably... Fubuki-senpai? Yes.
えっと、下？はい、下です。オッケー、オッケー、オッケー
Uh, down? Yes, down. Okay, okay, okay.
ランプはバナナ
The lamp is banana.
えっと、右？右ですか？あ、右
Uh, right? Is it right? Ah, right.
はい、えっと、緑
Yes, uh, green.
右？はい、右です
Right? Yes, right.
で、バナナ。黄色です
And, banana. It's yellow.
下ですか？下です
Is it down? It's down.
はい、じゃ、ピアノ行きます。ピアノのランプはバナナです
Yes, now for the piano. The piano lamp is banana.
バナナ... バナナ...
Banana... banana...
そんなバナナ...
Such banana...
バニャニャニャ...
Banyanyanya...
えっと、フブキ先輩が多分ナンバーがなんかと...
Uh, Fubuki-senpai can probably see what the number is...
見えるっぽいです。けど、あ、りぃちゃん？
...or something. But, ah, Ri-chan?
え、動いてない？先輩
Wait, are you not moving, senpai?
あっ
Ah.
生きてますか？
Are you alive?
時間が...
The time is...
時間がない！
There's no time!
バナナ食べます？
Want to eat a banana?
さようなら
Goodbye.
ああー！
Ahhh!
マジで分からん。あの、4つの数字が F-A-C-F って載ってたんだけど
I seriously don't get it. Those four letters were shown as F-A-C-F...
Fだったら、えっと、え、えっと、4。Fだったら4
If it's F, then uh... 4. If it's F, it's 4.
あ、これを1個ずつ教えてあげなきゃいけなかったんだ
Ah, we had to tell her these one by one.
はい、これをあげます。あ...
Yes, I'll send you this. Ah...
えっと、グループチャットはないから、フブキ先輩は...
Uh, since we don't have a group chat, Fubuki-senpai...
えっと、どこだっけ？
Uh, where was it?
これ送ってあげるんだ
I'll send this to you.
F...あ、え、ランプは全部変わらないから、左、左の数字から教えればいいってこと？そうそうそうそう。
F... Ah, since the lamps don't change, we just need to say starting from the left number? Right, right, right.
これ、ノートの、あの、番号チャートです
This is the note number chart.
ありがとう、ありがとう。ちょっとネットで探しました
Thank you, thank you. I searched for it online a bit.
そうそうそう
Right, right.
なんかその、4つ、4つある数字の何を教えたらいいのか分からんかったんよ、その。何番目って数字は分かるんだけど
I didn't know which of those four numbers I should tell you. I knew the numbers and their order, but...
あ、そう。数字を全部1個ずつ言っていけばよかったんだよ
Ah, right. You just had to say the numbers one by one.
はい
Yes.
じゃ、もしかして、なんか、C-D-C-D だったら、1-2-1-2 だから、1から...
So if it was C-D-C-D, it would be 1-2-1-2, so starting from 1...
あ、そう。それでいいのか。なんか、そうそうそう
Ah, right. Is that how it works? Yeah, yeah.
この、その4つの数字のどれを教えるんか分からんかったから
I didn't know which of those four numbers to say...
あの、コメントでなんか、この数字だよって言ってたんだけど、自分分かってないのに伝えても分からんから
...so in the comments they were saying "it's this number", but if I don't understand it myself, there's no point in telling you...
どうしようかなと思って。ちょっと1回、みんなに聞いた方がいいなと思って、これ
...so I didn't know what to do. I thought it'd be better to ask everyone first.
うわ、全部だね、あれは。左から順番に、って感じだった。オッケーオッケー。
Wow, it was all of them. It felt like we had to do it in order from left to right. Okay, okay.
はい、じゃ、次！
Okay, next!
フブキ先輩の声が... ちょっと低めに... 誰ですか、あなた？イナですか？
Fubuki-senpai's voice... is a bit deep... Who are you? Are you Ina?
私がイナです
I am Ina.
あ、フレアですか？
Ah, are you Flare?
あ、フレアですね。はい。えーっと、じゃあですね、えーっと、
Ah, you're Flare. Yes. Well then, let's see...
じゃ、ピアノから行こうかな。左下のピアノから行きます。はい。えーっと、ランプはイエロー、黄色、バナナです
Let's start with the piano. Let's go with the piano on the bottom left. Yes. Uh, the lamp is yellow, banana.
で、ナンバーは3です。3。
And the number is 3. 3.
バナナ。ナンバー教えてあげてください、ナンバー
Banana. Tell me the number, please, the number.
3です。ナンバーは3です
It's 3. The number is 3.
き、ランプは黄色です。ナンバーは分かんないです
Yel- The lamp is yellow. I don't know the number.
ナンバーは3... みんなから聞いてください。あ、マリク、若干マリクです。どうも、マリクです
The number is 3... Please ask everyone. Ah, Marik, it's slightly Marik. Hello, I'm Marik.
遊戯王から来ました。マリク。闇のマリクです。番号教えて！
I came from Yu-Gi-Oh. Marik. I am Yami Marik. Tell me the number!
...ください
...please.
ランプは黄色です
The light is yellow.
5、5だそうです。5。
It's 5. 5.
D3、G3、B3
D3, G3, B3.
OK、OK、OK。じゃあ次はなんですかね？
Okay, okay, okay. What's next?
はい、マリックです。
Yes, Marik is here.
マリックにも分かるように
So that even Marik can understand,
教えてください。
please explain it to me.
まだイエローです。2番目です。
It's still yellow. The second one.
なんですか？
What is it?
Gの次の番号を...
Tell me the next key after G,
次のあれを教えてください。
tell me the next one.
まだ3ですよ。
It's still 3.
あ、お、はい、はい、はい。
Ah, oh, yes, yes, yes.
まだ色とナンバーは変わりません。
The color and number haven't changed yet.
次はさっき教えてもらった5番目のやつの
Next is the fifth one you told me before,
Gの次の番号... 暗いです。
the key after G... It's dark.
7番目...ということは7番目です。7番目。
Number 7... That means the seventh one. Seventh.
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7... はい、はい、はい。
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7... Yes, yes, yes.
OKです。じゃあ次。
Okay. What's next?
さっきのがBでしたね。
The last one was B.
次が...なんだ？なんですか？
Next is... what? What is it?
マリックにも分かるように教え...
Explain it so Marik can understand...
2です！2です！2です。
It's 2! It's 2! It's 2.
OKです。はい、じゃあ最後です。
Okay. Yes, now for the last one.
マリックにも分かるように教え... 5番！
Explain it so Marik can understand... Number 5!
また5番目です。5番目。
It's the fifth one again. Fifth.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
はい、これコンプリート。
Okay, that's complete.
じゃあ続いて右上の点字いきます。
Next, we go to the braille on the top right.
十字キーがついてます。点字です。
There's a D-pad. It's braille.
7。あ、7だ。
7. Oh, it's 7.
ランプはブルーです。
The light is blue.
ブルー7です。
It's Blue 7.
ブルー7？ブルー7。
Blue 7? Blue 7.
なんかマリックが喋ってるでしょうか？
Wait, is Marik the one speaking?
ブルー7。ブルー7。
Blue 7. Blue 7.
ああ、イナさんにあの、点字の数字を...
Ah, I need to tell Ina the braille number...
ブルー7です。7です。
It's Blue 7. 7.
いや、でもこれ、聞こえてますよね。
Wait, but I can hear you clearly.
ブルーアイズの7！
Blue-Eyes 7!
上ですか？下ですか？右ですか？左ですか？
Is it up? Is it down? Is it right? Is it left?
あ、間違えました。
Oh, I made a mistake.
下だそうです。下です！
It's down. Down!
間違えました。下です、イナさん、これ。下です。
I made a mistake. It's down, Ina, down.
間違えました。
I made a mistake.
新しいものです。
It's a new one.
え、下じゃない？じゃ、なんなんですか？
Eh, not down? Then what is it?
新しいものになって、あの、ランプ多分変わっ...
It reset, and the light probably changed...
ランプブルーです。あ、ランプごめんなさい、グリーンです。
The light is blue. Ah, sorry, green.
ランプ緑です。ランプ緑。
The light is green. Green.
緑で2です。2。
Green 2. 2.
上です！上です！イナさん。
Up! Up, Ina!
Okay, okay, okay.
OKです。続いて、ランプは...
Okay. Next, the light is...
ランプは黄色です。バナナ。バナナの8です。
The light is yellow. Banana. Banana 8.
バナナ8。
Banana 8.
マリック、バナナ好き。
Marik likes bananas.
え、これは右ですか？
Eh, is it right?
右です、イナさん。右。はい、はい、はい。
It's right, Ina. Right. Yes, yes, yes.
OKです。続いて、ブルーアイズです。
Okay. Next is Blue-Eyes.
1、1です。
1. It's 1.
あと右、あと右です。イナさん。右です。
Next is right, right, Ina. Right.
Okay, okay.
OKです。続いて、レッドアイズ。
Okay. Next is Red-Eyes.
えーっと、4、4。
Ummm, 4. 4.
ブラックドラゴン、レッドアイ... 上です、イナさん！
Black Dragon, Red-Eye... Up, Ina!
上です！はい、はい、はい。
Up! Yes, yes, yes.
OKです。クリアしました。続いて計算です！
Okay. Cleared. Next is the math!
計算してください！
Please calculate this!
60 + 22 は 82。
60 + 22 is 82.
82ですか？
82?
あ、爆発します！
Ah, it's gonna explode!
壊れちゃった、フブちゃんが。
Fubu-chan is completely broken.
下って言ったでしょうが！
I told you it was "Down"!
でも、めっちゃ綺麗に聞こえてましたよ。
But I could hear you really clearly.
すっごい聞こえてた。全くノイキャン入らなかったけど。
You could hear me so well. The noise canceling didn't work at all.
完全にマリックだと聞こえるんだ。
So when it's Marik, it completely gets through!
じゃ、もう一回行こうか。
Shall we try one more time?
おお、お、お疲れ様です。
Oh, good job.
またマリックです。誰ですか？イナですか？
It's Marik again. Who is it? Is it Ina?
フブキ...イナですか？イナです、イナです。
Fubu... Is it Ina? It's Ina, it's Ina.
フブキ？イナです。
Fubuki? It's Ina.
イナ？イナです。
Ina? It's Ina.
あ、イナですか。イナさんですね。
Ah, it's Ina. It's Ina-san.
じゃ、ちょっとマリック側がちょっと...
Then, Marik will just...
笑わないで。気をつけて。
Don't laugh. Be careful.
点、点、点の十字ついてるやついきましょう。
Let's go to the one with the dots and a cross.
点、点、点の十字。はい。
Dots and a cross. Yes.
ランプは赤です。あと、喋れますよ、フブキさんは。
The light is red. Also, Fubuki can speak, you know.
ランプは赤です。3番だ。
The light is red. It's number 3.
えーっと、点字は3です。
Ummm, the braille is 3.
左です。左。
Left. Left.
素晴らしいです。続いて、バナナです。
Wonderful. Next is banana.
色はバナナです。バナナ。
The color is banana. Banana.
4番。バナナ4番。4番です。
Number 4. Banana 4. It's 4.
下です。下。OKです。
Down. Down. Okay.
じゃあ、続いてが、ブルーアイズです。ブルーです。ブルー。
Next is Blue-Eyes. Blue. Blue.
フブちゃん、ふざけだしちゃった。
Fubu-chan is starting to mess around.
ブルーの5番です。ブルーの5、上。
It's Blue 5. Blue 5, up.
下、上！上です、上。
Down, up! Up, up.
次が、グリーンの...
Next is Green...
グリーンです。はい、オールグリーン。
It's green. Yes, all green.
何番ですか？あ、番号は7です。
What number is it? Ah, the number is 7.
グリーンの7。
Green 7.
上です！
Up!
うえ、うえ。オッケー、クリア。
Up, up. Okay, clear.
続いて計算です。
Next is calculations.
はい、56たす35はわかりま…
Okay, 56 plus 35 is... I don't know!
56たす35は、なに、91？
56 plus 35 is... what, 91?
91。 / 91かもしれないです。
91. / It might be 91.
91って、これは偶数なのか奇数…
91... is that even or odd...
ランプは緑です。これはどっちですか？
The light is green. Which one is it?
偶数ナンバーですか？ 2？
An even number? 2?
2？ / 2。
2? / 2.
クリアしました。続いてピアノです。ピアノ。
We cleared it. Next is the piano! Piano!
ピアノですか？ピアノ行きます。
Piano? I'll do the piano.
Eの、Eの3から始めます。E3。
We'll start from E, E3. E3.
ナンバーは？
What's the number?
C3、D3、E3、D3、C3、D3...
C3, D3, E3, D3, C3, D3...
ブルー、ブルーの3か？
Blue... Blue 3?
全然わからない。 / 1、1ですって、1。
I have no idea. / It says 1, 1. 1.
あ、くらいですね。これも。オッケー。
Ah, it's dark. This one too. Okay.
次が、2。1、2。
Next is 2. 1, 2.
2。次が、1。
2. Next is 1.
最後が、3。3。
Lastly, 3. 3.
素晴らしい、バナナもらいました。
Splendid! I got a banana.
素晴らしい。 / 素晴らしいバナナ、バナナ。
Splendid. / Splendid banana, banana!
バナナやめてよね。 / やかましすぎるから。
Stop with the "banana". / You're way too loud.
そんなことないって、だって一個口開けたらさ、ガサガサってさ。
That's not true! I mean, as soon as I open my mouth, it gets all noisy.
チンパンジーやめてよね。チンパンジー。
Stop acting like a chimpanzee. Chimpanzee.
チンパンジーやめてよね。 / あ、また！
Stop being a chimpanzee. / Ah, again!
また、またこれ？
Again? This one again?
またダブっちゃうやつ。 / 嫌なやつ。
It's the duplicate one again. / The annoying one.
あ、いなーのですか。
Ah, is it Ina's turn?
これなんだ、これ。
What is this? What's this?
計算から行きます。58たす3はいくつですか？これ。61？
I'll start with calculations. How much is 58 plus 3? 61?
60だろ。
It's 60, right?
60、60、61。
60, 60, 61.
ランプはブルーアイスです。ブルー。
The light is blue. Blue.
61、えっと。
61... let's see.
え、ゼロがないんですけど。
Eh, there is no zero.
ランプブルーです。
The light is blue.
あー、え？
Ah... what?
ランプブルー。
Light is blue.
え、61って偶数ですか、奇数ですか？
Is 61 even or odd?
奇数。
Odd.
あ、お、お。
Ah, oh, oh.
ない。
Nothing.
ない？
Nothing?
おー、ちょっと待って。手が見えない。手！
Oh, wait a minute. I can't see my hands! My hands!
え、どっち、9？
Wait, which one, 9?
え、番号わかんない、これわかんない。
Eh, I don't know the numbers, I don't get this.
これ、私の動きを見て、フブキング。
Watch my movements, Fubucking!
あ、61は何ですか？
Ah, what's 61?
私の動きを見て！
Watch my movements!
ゼロです。ゼロ。
It's zero. Zero.
フブキちゃん、酔った？大丈夫そう？
Fubuki-chan, are you drunk? Are you okay?
何、これ。
What is this?
ボディランゲージ。
Body language.
でも、9。9なの、10なの、どっちなの？
But, 9? Is it 9 or 10, which one?
え、ジェスチャーこれ？ゼロって、これ、丸書いてました、丸。ないです。
Wait, is this a gesture? A zero? She drew a circle, a circle. There's none.
あ、じゃ、続いて、記号です。右上。記号行きましょう。
Ah, then next is symbols. Top-right. Let's do symbols.
音のなる記号教えてください。
Tell me the symbol that makes a sound.
えっと、なんか丸に縦線入ってるやつ。
Uh, the one with a circle and a vertical line through it.
はいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes.
あ、縦線が入ってますか。
Ah, there's a vertical line?
赤、赤、赤、赤、赤。
Red, red, red, red, red.
えーっと。丸に、あ、アンテナで一番下ですね。これ一番下。
Let's see. A circle with... Ah, the antenna, so it's the bottom one. This bottom one.
あ、違う？ / 違う、それじゃない。
Ah, wrong? / No, not that one.
すいません、間違えた。
Sorry, I made a mistake.
え、音鳴るのは、トライアングルに、え、線が入ってます。あ、オッケーオッケーです。
Ah, the one making a sound is a triangle with a line. Ah, okay, okay.
普通の三角形の方ね。
The normal triangle one, right?
トライアングルの上に線、あ、グリーンなので一番下です。
A line on top of the triangle. Ah, it's green, so it's the very bottom.
ナイス！じゃ、次の音のなるもの教えてください。
Nice! Tell me the next one that makes a sound.
次は、え、スターですね。あ、星じゃないスターですね。
Next is, uh, star. Ah, not a celestial star, but "Star".
普通のスター、オッケー。
A normal star, okay.
えー、2番目だから、赤。
Uh, it's the second one, so red.
お、赤なんで一番下です。
Oh, it's red, so it's the bottom-most.
オッケー。 / オッケー。
Okay. / Okay.
次。
Next.
丸に縦線。
Circle with a vertical line.
あ、これはまた、あの丸に、縦線が真ん中に入ってますね。
Ah, this is another circle with a vertical line in the middle.
え、あ、3回目？3回目ですか？
Eh, ah, the third one? Is it the third stage?
丸に、縦線。
Circle with a vertical line.
赤、これ、赤？
Red, is this red?
本当か？
Really?
赤、真ん中だ、真ん中。
Red is the middle one, middle one.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。最後。
Okay, okay, okay. Last one.
線の星。
Star with lines.
線のスターだ。
It's the star with lines.
あ、赤なんで真ん中ですね。
Ah, it's red, so it's the middle one.
おお、素晴らしい。やばい、時間ない。ピアノです、ピアノ。
Oh, splendid! Oh no, there's no time. Piano, piano!
Cから、Cから始まる5です。
Start from C, C-5.
5、えーっと、Aは6。
5... let's see, A is 6.
やばい、時間。6、6、6。
Oh no, time! 6, 6, 6.
ろく、ろく！
6! 6!
え？なんだっけ？色なんだっけ？
Wait, what was it? What color was it?
色なんだっけ？
What color was it?
やば、あと20秒！
Oh no, 20 seconds left!
助けて！
Help!
おお、どうした？
Oh, what's wrong?
Cから始まりました。
It starts with C.
バナナ、バナナ、バナナ！
Banana, banana, banana!
Cのなん、なんですか？5？
Which C? Is it 5?
C、C、C...
C, C, C...
え、助けて！
Wait, help!
ご、ご、ご、ご、ご！
5, 5, 5, 5, 5!
ご、ご！
5, 5!
あときゅう...
And then 9...
ろく
ろく、ろく、ろく！
6, 6, 6!
よん、よん
4, 4
よん、よん、よん、よん...
4, 4, 4, 4...
あー！
Oh no!
惜しい！
So close!
あと1秒あったらクリアできたのに！
We could have cleared it with just one more second!
あー、色忘れてちょっとわちゃわちゃしました。
Ah, I forgot the color, so I panicked a bit.
バナナだったのに。
Even though it was banana.
ば、ば、ば、バナナだったのに。
Ba-ba-ba-banana...
あるある。
It happens.
これはモンキー失格です。
This is a disqualification as a monkey.
モンキー失格！
Monkey disqualification!
まあ、イナはタコだから。
Well, Ina is an octopus, so...
確かにタコだし。イナはタコだしな。
True, you are an octopus. Indeed, you are.
人間ですけど。
But I'm a human.
人間。人間です。
Human. You're a human.
次行きます。
Moving on to the next.
あ。
Ah.
結構あるね。
There are quite a few.
えーっと、じゃあ、えーっと、シンボルと...
Let's see... So, the symbols and...
シンボルから行きますか。えっと、左上、はいはいはい。
Should we start with the symbols? Top left, okay, got it.
えっと、線の、線の星。
Um, the star with a line.
バナナ。えっと、真ん中のボタンお願いします。あ、間違えた。
Banana. The middle button, please. Ah, my bad.
線の星、です。
It's the star with a line.
みどり。え、一番下のボタンお願いします、はい。
Green. The bottom-most button, please. Yes.
えっと、えっと、えっと、丸いのです。縦線なんですけど、線が長いです。
It's a circle with a vertical line, but the line is long.
みどり。一番下のボタンお願いします、はい。
Green. The bottom button, please. Yes.
え、線の星です。
The star with a line.
あ、真ん中のボタンお願いします、はい。
Ah, the middle button, please. Yes.
え、次の音は、どっちですか？
What is the next sound?
また、あ...
Again, ah...
えっと、砂時計なんですけど、えー、三角、三角。
It's an hourglass, but... triangle, triangle.
三角の緑。一番下お願いします、ボタン、はい。オッケーオッケー。
Green triangle. The bottom button, please. Yes. Okay, okay.
じゃ、次は、えっと、真ん中で、てんてんてんでディレクションボタン、行きます。
Next, the middle direction button with dots.
え、ランプは青です。
The lamp is blue.
え、え？あ、えっと、ランプが青くて、真ん中で、番号が、
Wait, what? Ah, the lamp is blue, in the middle, and the number is...
あ、上、上です。
Ah, up. It's up.
オッケー。え、ランプが赤。
Okay. The lamp is red.
え、右ですか？
Is it right?
オッケー、右です。
Okay, it's right.
で、ランプが緑。
And the lamp is green.
え、左？左です。
Left? It's left.
えっと、ランプが赤。
The lamp is red.
え、右？右です。
Right? It's right.
オッケー、次はピアノ行きます。
Okay, next is the piano.
ピアノはランプが...
For the piano, the lamp is...
黄色です。バナナ、黄色。
Yellow. Banana, yellow.
え、3。
3.
あ、ちょっと手が見えないんです。
Ah, I can't really see the hands.
えっと、7？
Is it 7?
はい、7です。
Yes, it's 7.
あ、あ、あ、最初から行かないと、えっと、ランプ、
Ah, we have to start over. The lamp...
え、ランプ黄色で、
The lamp is yellow...
番号が、
and the number is...
え、3。
3.
オッケー、次は、
Okay, next is...
1。
1.
次は、
Next is...
2。
2.
次は、
Next is...
5。
5.
あ、ギリギリ！
Ah, so close!
押し... ギリギリ押せなかった。
Almost... I couldn't press it at the very last second.
いや、大丈夫です。
No, it's okay.
いや、でもナイスでした。
But that was a nice try.
いや、ここクリアしたいな。これをクリアして最後にしようか。
I want to clear this. Let's make this the last one.
あ、オッケーです。
Ah, okay.
オッケー。じゃあ、どうしよう。イナのモジュール最近やってないからじゃあ...
Okay. Since we haven't done Ina's modules recently...
イナのモジュールやるか。
should we do Ina's module?
モジュール、えっと、これですね。はい。
The module... let's see, this one. Yes.
あ、じゃあ、それじゃないかな。目隠してるやつ。
Ah, then isn't it that one? The one covering eyes.
あ、それです、はい。
Ah, that's the one. Yes.
で、じゃあ、フレアが、じゃあ、あの口塞いでるやついっとく？
And should Flare do the one with the mouth covered?
私が、モジュール見てるやつと...
I'll do the one looking at the modules, and...
伝える方がいいか、それがいい。伝える方で。
Is communicating better? That's good. In communicating.
それでいってみよう、しばらく。
Let's go with that for a bit.
うん、これでいってみよう。オッケー？
Yeah, let's try this. Okay?
はい。
Yes.
いけるか？すごい久しぶりになると... じゃあ簡単なのからいきます。
Can we do it? Since it's been a while, let's start with the easy ones.
はい。
Yes.
ええと、ケーブルいきます。1ページのやつです。
Okay, starting with the cables. The one-page one.
4本あります。ランプが黄色です。
There are four of them. The lamp is yellow.
ええと、一番左切ってください。
Please cut the leftmost one.
ナイス。
Nice.
ええと、次は、どうしようかな。ピアノいきますか。
Next... what should we do? Shall we go with the piano?
ピアノで、
Piano,
ランプが、ええ、緑です。
the lamp is green.
6です。
It's 6.
ええ、4番。
Okay, number 4.
ええ、3番。3番。
Okay, number 3. Number 3.
3？オッケー。
3? Okay.
ええ、2番。
Okay, number 2.
オッケー。
Okay.
めっちゃ上手い。
You're so good.
1番。
Number 1.
1番。オッケー。
Number 1. Okay.
素晴らしい。で、次が記号のやつです。
Wonderful. Next is the symbol one.
あ。
Ah.
音が、ええ、鳴ったのは丸に縦線入ってるやつです。
The sound that played is the circle with a vertical line.
端、線が長いです。線が長い、やつです。
But the line is long. It's the one with the long line.
え、赤だから一番上押してください。
Ah, it's red, so please press the topmost one.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
次が、ランプが黄色、緑、赤で...
Next, the lamp is yellow, green, red...
あ、砂時計、丸い砂時計です。
Ah, the hourglass... it's a round hourglass.
あ、丸い、え、丸くない砂時計？
Ah, round... wait, not round hourglass?
半円の砂時計です。
It's a semi-circle hourglass.
え、赤が一番下押してください。
For red, please press the bottommost one.
はい。
Yes.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
次は、丸に縦線入ってるやつで、
Next is the one with a vertical line inside a circle...
線が長いです。
and the line is long.
黄色。えっと、一番下お願いします。
Yellow. The bottommost one, please.
オッケー。
Okay.
ええ、三角形に上に線が1本入ってるやつです。
Okay, the triangle with a single line at the top.
一番下です。
It's the bottommost one.
おお、完璧すぎてやばい。
Wow, that was too perfect, amazing.
おお！すごい！すごい！
Oh! Amazing! Amazing!
早っ！ノーミス、ノーミス、めっちゃ早かった。
So fast! No mistakes, no mistakes, it was super fast.
すごい！すごい！やった！
Amazing! Amazing! We did it!
ピアノのやつ大変やねんな。
The piano one is tough, isn't it?
今からレベル15なんだけど、
We're starting level 15 now,
今まで難易度が、なんか難易度の下にトランクがあって、
but before, there was a trunk below the difficulty level,
はい。
Yes.
カラーがブルーだったんだけど、
and its color was blue,
レベル15からはトランクの色がなんか茶色になった。
but from level 15, the trunk's color changed to brown.
へえ。え？あ、本当だ。
Huh. Eh? Ah, you're right.
あ、新しいモジュールが。
Ah, a new module...
これだけやって終わってみようか、新しいの。
Let's just try this one and end it, the new one.
オッケー。はい。
Okay. Yes.
じゃあちょっと新しいのいってみ。
Let's go for the new one.
なんだろう。
I wonder what it is.
ああ、新しいものありますよ、はい。
Ah, there is a new thing, yes.
簡単なのから、むず、難しいのからいく？
Should we go from easy, or difficult, difficult first?
あ、簡単のからいきましょう。
Ah, let's start with the easy ones.
52引く29は？わかりません。
52 minus 29 is? I don't know.
あ、50... え？
Ah, 50... eh?
52引く29は？エル、急いで。計算して。
52 minus 29 is? L, hurry up. Calculate it.
ちょっと計算のやついきます。
I'll go with the calculation one.
50... 50...何？
50... 50... what?
23。
23.
23。えっと、2... 3...
23. Let's see, 2... 3...
これ確かに、確かにフブちゃん、イナかな？聞こえる。で、あ、ランプが青。
This is definitely Fubu-chan? Ina? I can hear it. And, ah, the lamp is blue.
オッケー。
Okay.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
次は新しいやつです。
Next is the new one.
上にランプが4つ付いてて、
There are four lamps at the top,
え、ナンバーもあります。
and there are also numbers.
なんか真ん中にエンターって書いてるやつ、これ、レバーかな？
There's something written "Enter" in the middle, is this a lever?
えっと、えっと、左からナンバーは、9...
Well, the numbers from the left are 9...
左からグリーン、ブルー、レッド、イエローです。
From the left, they're green, blue, red, yellow.
グリーン、ブルー、レッド、イエロー。
Green, blue, red, yellow.
ナンバーも欲しいですかね？
Do you also want the numbers?
ナンバーは、9、6、3、7です。
The numbers are 9, 6, 3, 7.
何だこれ？番号で伝えればいいのかな？
What is this? Should I convey it by numbers?
あ、番号...
Ah, numbers...
...ですかね？
...is it?
黄色だから、一番右です。
Since it's yellow, it's the far right one.
オッケー。
Okay.
次が赤から、右から二番目。
Next is red, so second from the right.
右から二番目？
Second from the right?
そう。
Yes.
オッケー。
Okay.
次は...
Next is...
次が...
青？
Blue?
青。
Blue.
青ですか？
Is it blue?
青です。あと右から二番目です。
It's blue. Also, second from the right.
右... あ、ごめん、あ、空いてない...
Right... Ah, sorry, it's not open...
まだ押してないやつだから、左から二番目。
It's one we haven't pressed yet, so second from the left.
左から二番目。オッケー。
Second from the left. Okay.
じゃあ、最後がこれ。
Then, the last one is this.
緑かな？
Green, maybe?
これですね。
This one, right?
あ、あれ？
Ah, huh?
あ、あ、どうかな？何だろう？
Ah, how is it? What could it be?
リセットしました。えっと...
It reset. Let's see...
でも、ランプ一緒... あ、待って、これ数字付いてるね。点字付いてる？
But the lamps are the same... Ah, wait, it has numbers on it. Does it have braille?
はい。9, 6, 3, 7。
Yes. 9, 6, 3, 7.
あ、なるほど、色と、数字かな、これ。
Ah, I see, colors and, maybe numbers, for this?
もう一回、ランプの色から言います。
Let's do the lamp colors again.
えっと、グリーン、左からグリーン、ブルー、レッド、イエローです。
Um, green, from left: green, blue, red, yellow.
で、フブちゃん... あ、イナ？
And, Fubuchan... ah, Ina?
はい。
Yes.
す、数字を伝えてあげてください。
Te-Tell me the numbers.
えっと、左から9, 6, 3, 7です。
Let's see, from left it's 9, 6, 3, 7.
右がイナかな、たぶん。モジュールやってたよね、確か。
Right is Ina, probably. You were doing a module, right?
確かモジュールです、はい。
Indeed, it is a module, yes.
うわ、なんか難しそうな。
Whoa, this looks kinda difficult.
上、ん？上？
Up, huh? Up?
たぶん、これって、左が上とか...
Maybe, for this, left is up or...
い、色、色じゃなくて？
Co-Color? Not color?
あ、なるほど。左が上で。
Ah, I see. Left is up, right?
上。青も上。っていいのかな？
Up. Blue is also up. Is that right?
青も上。
Blue is also up.
これも上。
This is also up.
赤は？
How about red?
下。えっと、次が下。
Down. Um, the next one is down.
はい。
Okay.
で、黄色が上。一番右が上です。
And yellow is up. The far right is up.
オッケー。おお！
Okay. Oh!
おおおー！できた！
Ooh! We did it!
できたー！すごい！
We did it! Incredible!
素晴らしい！
Splendid!
やばかった！これ、難いぞ！これ！
That was crazy! This is tough, this!
いや、数字気づかなかった、最初。ごめんね。
But man, I didn't notice the numbers at first. Sorry!
いや、いや、全然、全然！これ大変だった。
No, no, not at all, not at all! This was tough.
まず上のランプの色を教えてもらって、で、イナに数字を教えてもらって、照らし合わせた時に、
First, you had to tell me the lamp colors, then Ina had to tell you the numbers, and when we cross-referenced...
例えば一番最初のランプが青だった時に、一番最初の数字は偶数か奇数かみたいな。
For example, if the first lamp was blue, whether the first number was even or odd.
へえー！
Whoa!
ええー。
Wow.
次のランプが黄色だった時に、5より数字が上か下かとか。
When the next lamp was yellow, whether the number was higher or lower than 5.
うわ、むず！
Whoa, hard!
次緑だった場合、赤いランプの数字より上か下かみたいな。
If the next was green, whether it was higher or lower than the red lamp's number.
へえー！
Whoa!
だから、メモ、メモって、そう、色と数字をメモっとかないと、分からなかった、たぶん、これ。
So, you have to write it down, yeah, if you don't take notes of the colors and numbers, you probably wouldn't get it.
今後はなんかメモがないと難しいですね。
From now on, it's going to be difficult without taking notes.
難しいね、メモがないと。
It's tough without notes.
もう、もう、ごちゃごちゃになるレベルになってきたんや。
We've reached the level where things are getting all jumbled up.
いや、もう、もうごちゃごちゃだったの。
Man, it was already so jumbled up.
もう分からなかった、分からなかった。でも、ここまでクリアできた。
I didn't get it, didn't get it at all. But, we managed to clear up to here.
いや、素晴らしい！
No, that was wonderful!
クリアできましたよ！わーい！
We cleared it! Yay!
すごい、上手かった。素晴らしい。
Awesome, you guys were great. Wonderful.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
いや、面白かった、これ。
No, this was fun, this.
いや、これ、いくつまであるんだろうね。
Man, how many of these are there, I wonder.
ね、まだまだあるっぽい。他にもやってないモジュールあったしね、マニュアル。
Right, seems like there's still more. There were other modules we haven't done in the manual too.
そうですね、はい、いっぱいありました。なんか。
That's true, yes, there were plenty. Somehow.
読みたくなかったんですけど、ちょっと見たら...
I didn't want to read it, but when I took a peek...
なに、これ？
What's this?
ゾッとするやついっぱいあったけど。
There were plenty of spine-chilling ones.
ね、多分、だから4つのカラーもあったっぽいしね、多分。
Right, probably, there seemed to be four colors too, probably.
いや、とんでもなかった。いや、でも面白かった、ありがとう。
No, that was crazy. But it was fun, thank you.
面白かった！面白かったです。
It was fun! It was fun.
楽しかった。
It was enjoyable.
ありがとう。イナもありがとうね。
Thank you. Thanks to you too, Ina.
いえ、ありがとうございました！本当に、なんか。
Not at all, thank you very much! Truly, somehow...
楽しかったです。
It was fun.
なんか、あの、徹夜してて...
Somehow, um, I stayed up all night...
徹夜しとるんかい！
You stayed up all night?!
なんか寝て起きたらもう5時で、DM確認したらフブキ先輩から「これやる？」って。
I fell asleep and woke up at 5, and when I checked DM, Fubuki-senpai was like, "Wanna do this?"
「あ、やろうかな」って。
And I was like, "Ah, guess I'll do it."
ゲリラで突発的にくる。
Getting a sudden guerilla stream.
やってよかったです、いやー。
I'm glad I did it, whew.
いや、いいよね、これね、面白かった。これ日本語全然分からないメンバーでも面白そうやな、これ。
No, this is great, this was fun. Even with members who don't know Japanese at all, this looks like it'd be fun.
そうですね。どう伝えるか。
True. How to convey it.
見てみたいです。
I want to watch it.
ね、どう伝えるか。そう、英語で理解した人たちはどう伝えるのか。
Right, how to convey it. Yeah, how people who understood it in English would convey it.
はい、面白かった。じゃあ、今日ありがとう。お疲れ様！
Yes, that was fun. Well, thank you for today. Thanks for your hard work!
お疲れ様でした！
Thanks for your hard work!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
うわ、バナナ！
Wow, banana!
バナナ
Banana
一伊那爾栖
Ninomae Ina'nis